At this time, brothers and sisters, we
will have the reading of the law.
We're going to begin in Exodus 20. We're
going to read verses 1-1 17.
Exodus 20:es 1-1 17.
When you get it, my brother, go ahead
and read.
>> And God spake all these words, saying, I
am the Lord thy God, which have brought
thee out of the land of Egypt, out of
the house of bondage. Thou shalt have no
other gods before me. Thou shalt not
make unto thee any grave in image or any
likeness of anything that is in heaven
above, or that is in the earth beneath,
or that is in the water under the earth.
Thou shalt not bow down thyself to them,
nor serve them. For I, the Lord thy God,
am a jealous God, visiting the iniquity
of the fathers upon the children unto
the third and fourth generation of them
that hate me, and showing mercy of the
thousands of them that love me, and keep
my commandments. Thou shalt not take the
name of the Lord thy God in vain. For
the Lord will not hold him guiltless
that taketh his name in vain. Remember
the Sabbath day to keep it holy. Sixth
day shalt thou labor and do all thy
work, but the seventh day is the Sabbath
of the Lord thy God. In it thou shalt
not do any work, thou nor thy son, nor
thy daughter, thy man's servant, nor thy
man's servant, nor thy cattle, nor thy
stranger that is within thy gates. For
in six days the Lord made heaven and
earth, the sea, and all that in them is,
and rested the seventh day. Wherefore
the Lord blessed the Sabbath day, and
hallowed it, honor thy father and thy
mother, that thy days may be long upon
the land which the Lord thy God giveth
thee. Thou shalt not kill. Thou shalt
not commit adultery. Thou shalt not
steal. Thou shalt not bear false witness
against thy neighbor. Thou shalt not
covet thy neighbor's house. Thou shalt
not coveret thy neighbor's wife, nor his
man's servant, nor his man servant, nor
his ox, nor his ass, nor anything that
is thy neighbors.
>> And now, let's go to Ecclesiastes
12. We're going to read verses 13 and
14. Ecclesiastes 12:es 13 and 14. Go
ahead.
>> Let us hear the conclusion of the whole
matter. Fear God and keep his
commandments. For this is the whole duty
of man. For God shall bring every work
into judgment, with every secret thing,
whether it be good or whether it be
evil.
>> Now, let's go to Revelation chapter 22.
We're going to read verses 14 and 15.
Revelation 22
14 and 15. When you get it, brother, go
ahead and read it.
>> Blessed are they that do his
commandments, that they may have right
to the tree of life, and may enter in
through the gates into the city. For
without are dogs and sorcerers and
whoreongers and murderers and idolattors
and whosoever loveth and maketh a lie.
>> Let's thank God for the reading of his
law, brothers and sisters.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> Okay. Just a quick word on the law,
brothers and sisters. The law is
ordained to eternal life. Point blank.
Period.
>> Yes, sir.
>> When a rich young man asked Jesus, "What
good thing must I do to enter into
life?" What did the Lord reply?
>> Keep the commandments,
>> plain and simple, cut and dry. Isn't
that correct?
>> Amen.
>> So, the law was good. It is good and
it's going to always be good. Don't let
anybody ever tell you that because we're
under grace, we don't have to keep the
Lord's commandments.
>> Okay? Because somebody told me that
recently and I had to set them straight.
>> All right, brothers and sisters. All
right. First things first, I'd like to
introduce myself. My name is Brother
Marcus. I'm from the Riverdale class.
reading for us today is your very own
brother Byron. Okay,
we're going to do what we do at the
Israel of God, brothers and sisters.
We're going to get right into this
lesson. So, the title of today's lesson
is the purpose of the ministry service
unto salvation.
So, I want to say first of all, brothers
and sisters, is that this is the
ministry of Jesus. Okay?
He employs men to continue in the work
that he started. The father sent him
into into the world to reconcile,
redeem, and recover man. So once he did
his part, he entrusted this word
to brothers like myself to continue in
that same process. Are we following
brothers and sisters?
>> Yes, sir. But a lot of people don't even
understand where man fell from and what
God's plan and purpose was for creating
us in the first place. We're going to
show you that Adam's actions created a
condition that we could not remedy
ourselves. Brothers and sisters, so the
father sent Jesus into the world with
that plan to salvage that which was
shipwrecked from day number one. We're
going to see that. And as servants of
God, brothers and sisters, everything we
do is geared toward us obtaining the end
all be all, which is salvation.
>> So,
>> but there are all kinds of ministries
out there in the world today. You got
prosperity and
>> yes,
>> oh, if you're not doing well, you're not
blessed and all this kind of stuff. You
got Hebrews that are caught up in the
flesh. When they do talk about
salvation, they talk about only Israel,
meaning the physical seed of Jacob,
being saved. Right. And then you got the
Sunday preachers who say we already
saved so we don't have to do any works.
And that time people die they go off,
you know, get two wings. I think you
know
>> they get two wings and they get raptured
off to heaven at some point in time. But
we're going to show you these things
couldn't be further from the truth.
We're going to deal with some specific
things by the time we get out of here to
show you what brothers like myself are
supposed to be doing for you. Yes, I am
standing in the gap, brothers and
sisters.
>> Amen.
>> Because as a gap was created, again,
we're going to show you when Adam sinned
against God, between God and man, that
caused this separation, not only
spiritually, but physically as well,
because the Lord was right here on the
earth with his creation. Is that
correct? Yes, sir.
>> We're going to see these things, and
this is what we're going to deal with in
this lesson today. I'm going to show you
some specific things that brothers like
myself are supposed to be doing. I'm
supposed to walk this walk and be an
example, but I'm also post supposed to
study this word, get some knowledge,
wisdom, and understanding myself so that
I can impart that knowledge unto you,
brothers and sisters. That's what this
is all about, man. You all ready?
>> All right. So, it's a pleasure to stand
before you all on the Lord's Sabbath
day.
>> Let's kick this off in Genesis chapter
2, brothers and sisters. Y'all with me?
>> All right. Genesis chapter 2. Let's lay
a little foundation first. Genesis
chapter 2. We're going to read about the
creation of man.
Genesis chapter 2. Let's start at verse
7. My brother, when you get it, go ahead
and read that.
>> And the Lord God saw a man of the dust
of the ground and breathed into his
nostrils the breath of life.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And man became a living soul.
>> And man became a living soul. Before the
breath of life was added, he was a dead
soul. Brothers and sisters, we do not
have a soul inside of us. We are the
soul. Okay?
>> Go ahead and read, brother. And the Lord
God planted a garden eastward in Eden.
And there he put the man whom he had
formed.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And out of the ground made the Lord God
to grow every tree that is pleasant to
the sight and good for food.
>> Uh-huh.
>> The tree of life also in the midst of
the garden and the tree of knowledge of
good and evil.
>> Brothers and sisters, people read this,
don't understand it, but they want to
argue with you about what's in
Corinthians. This is Bible 101 right
here.
>> Yes. Once he formed this man, he put him
in this garden. And it says, "Out of the
ground made the Lord God to grow every
tree that is pleasant to the sight and
good for food." Those are physical
trees. Correct?
>> Yes.
>> Amen.
>> But then it says the tree of life also.
That means in addition to the physical
trees, you got another kind of tree
right here, right? Yes, sir.
>> The tree of life. And it says also the
tree of the knowledge of good and evil.
So we got two trees in the garden that
did not grow out of the ground.
>> Right,
>> brothers and sisters? These are symbolic
trees. These are spirit trees. Spiritual
trees that produce fruit as well. But
physical trees produce physical fruit.
Spiritual trees produce spiritual fruit.
You can go to St. John 6:63. The Lord
said, "It is the spirit that quickly the
flesh profitth nothing. The words that I
speak unto you, they are what, brothers
and sisters?"
>> Spirit and life.
>> So these two trees are going to tell you
some words, right?
>> Yes, sir. So this is what we need to
understand. Now let's skip down to verse
15 and continue. What does it say?
>> And the Lord God took the man and put
him into the garden of Eden to dress it
and to keep it.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And the Lord God commanded the man,
saying, "Of every tree of the garden,
thou mayest freely eat."
>> The first commandment he gave Adam, he
said, "Of every tree of God you may
freely eat." We're going to see that he
could have also eaten of the tree of
life. Cuz he's going to give one
exception. Read verse 17. What it say,
brother?
>> But of the tree of the knowledge of good
and evil. Uh-huh.
>> Thou shalt not eat of it. For in the day
that that Excuse me. For in the day that
thou eatest thereof, thou shalt surely
die.
>> He said, "But of the tree of the
knowledge of good and evil," we're going
to see that this is the serpent or
Satan, the devil. The day that you eat
of this tree is the day that you're
going to surely die. No question. Yes,
sir.
>> No doubt about it. So, before anything
went down, death was not a part of this
creation. Do we understand what we're
reading here, brothers and sisters?
Amen, sir. But let's continue again.
We're just laying the foundation. Let's
go right into chapter 3. Because Eve had
been brought forth, Adam's wife, and the
devil did not encounter Adam. He rolled
up on his wife. Let's see what happened.
3 and 1. What did it say, brother?
>> Now the serpent was more subtle than any
beast of the field which the Lord God
had made.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And he said unto the woman.
>> And he did what?
>> Said unto the woman.
>> Resist talk, brothers and sisters.
>> So this is not a literal snake. Again,
this is symbolism. Revelation the 12th
chapter give you all of the devil's
title.
>> Yes,
>> this is talking Satan. He was kicked out
of heaven and cast down to the earth.
He's in the garden and he's talking to
Eve. Start at the chapter three again,
brother.
>> Now the serpent was more subtle than any
beast of the field which the Lord God
had made.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And he said unto the woman, "Yeah, had
God said, you shall not eat of every
tree of the garden?"
>> So he's asking her a question, trying to
get her to engage in conversation. He
already know what the Lord said. He was
there. He was earhustling.
>> Yes.
>> But what what did he say? Go ahead.
>> And the woman said unto the serpent, "We
may eat of the fruit of the trees of the
garden,
>> but of the fruit of the tree which is in
the midst of the garden." God had said,
"Ye shall not eat of it, NEITHER SHALL
YOU TOUCH IT, lest you die."
>> Also Eve knew the commandment and the
consequences. Right?
>> She did.
>> But let's see what the serpent said.
Let's see what the devil said. Go ahead
and read.
>> And the serpent said unto the woman,
>> Uhhuh.
>> Ye shall not surely die.
>> What?
>> Ye shall not surely die. shall not
surely die. Brothers and sisters, the
first lie told in the book,
>> he just straight up contradicted and
diametrically opposed what thus sayeth
the Lord.
>> Do we see that?
>> Yes, sir.
>> In verse
17, the Lord said, if you eat of this
tree, you shall surely die. He just told
her, you shall not surely die. He's an
adversary, brothers and sisters.
>> And he's trying to get you and I are cut
off.
>> But what did he say? Go ahead and read
>> verse five. For God doth know that in
the day you eat thereof, then your eyes
shall be open, and ye shall be as gods,
knowing good and evil.
>> Wait a minute.
>> In Psalm 82, Jesus called us God.
>> Yes, sir.
>> He just said, "You shall be as God."
>> So God is offering you to be like him.
And Satan, the devil is offering her
right here to be as God, to be somewhat
like him.
>> Do y'all see this, brother?
>> Yes, sir.
>> But what it say? What did she do?
>> And when the woman saw that the tree was
good for food,
>> and that it was pleasant to the eyes,
and a tree to be desired to make one
wise,
>> she took of the fruit thereof, and did
eat, and gave also unto her husband with
her, and he did eat.
>> Again, in Psalm 82, it says, "How long
will you judge unjustly, and except the
person of the wicked?" It started right
here.
>> It says, "She saw that the tree was
good." This is her judgment, brothers
and sisters. But the Lord already gave
the commandment. Don't talk to this guy.
Okay? She said he's going to make you
wise. So she took the fruit thereof. In
other words, the fruit of his
conversation. She consumed his words,
which was bad enough. And then she
turned around and took to Adam and gave
it to him. And it says he did eat. So
she was in the transgression, but he
rolled right along with her. Isn't that
correct?
>> Yes.
>> That's what we're reading. But let's get
right down to the punishment that God
passed on man. We not we're not going to
deal with what he told Satan and the
woman. Let's go and see what he told
Adam because of his transgression. 17 My
brother, what did he say?
>> And unto Adam, he said, "Because thou
has hearkened unto the voice of thy
wife."
>> Because you hearkened unto the voice of
Satan, the devil, my brother,
>> has hearkened unto the voice of thy
wife.
>> Y'all notice this confirms that it was
words that he consumed.
>> Yes, sir.
>> She got that conversation from Satan
again and she took it to Adam. He
accepted it and it was the words he's
talking hearken to the voice of his
wife. The words she got from Satan the
devil. Did we see that brothers and
sisters?
>> Yes.
>> That's how they ate. Go ahead and read.
>> And hath eaten of the tree of which I
commanded thee, saying, "Thou shalt not
eat of it, purchase the ground for thy
sake."
>> And sorrow shalt thou eat of it all the
days of thy life.
>> Go ahead.
>> Thorns and thistles shall it bring forth
to thee, and thou shalt eat the herb of
the field.
>> What else?
>> In the sweat of thy face shalt thou eat
bread. Oh, now you got to work a little
hard. You just can't dress and keep the
garden and pick you some fruit off the
tree. Now you going to work.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Let's see how long. Go ahead and read.
>> Till thou return unto the ground.
>> Uhuh. Till I give you two wings and wrap
you off up HERE WITH ME.
>> TILL THOU RETURN unto the ground?
>> Oh, till thou return unto the ground.
Why, my brother?
>> For elephant was thou taken.
>> Uhhuh.
>> For dust thou art.
>> And what else?
>> And unto dust shalt thou return.
>> So man was taken from the dust. We read
that in 2 and seven, right?
>> Yes, sir. And it says, "Thus you are,
and unto dust shall you return." In
other words, I'm exacting this death
sentence on you that I told you before
you made this mistake. Are we following
the story, brothers and sisters?
>> Now, let's see what else happened. So,
death was put on the table right here.
It was not originally a part of Adam's
creation.
Skip down in verse 22 because something
else happened. Go ahead and read it.
What did it say? And the Lord God said,
"Behold, the man has become as one of us
to know good and evil."
>> Pay attention, brothers and sisters. Go
ahead and read.
>> And now, lest he put forth his hand and
take also of the tree of life and eat
and live forever.
>> I am confused. Didn't we read there were
two symbolic trees in the garden?
>> Yes, sir.
>> The tree of life and the tree of
knowledge of good and evil.
>> Now, they didn't ate and drank at the
table and the cup of the devil. But he
said, "Hey, if we leave him here, he can
put forth his hand." In other words, he
can make an effort and take also the
tree of life. In other words, listen to
Jesus like he listen to Satan, right?
>> Mhm.
>> It says, "And eat and live for how long,
my brother?"
>> Forever.
>> Brothers and sisters, do we see what was
on the table in the beginning from day
one?
>> Yes, Lord.
>> Adam could have listened to Jesus, ate
the fruit of his words, and learned how
to live forever. That's what the Lord
was doing. Brother Buie has that lesson.
God uh excuse me, man created to become
God. That was God's intention and
purpose for us from day one to create
beings like himself. Do we see that?
>> Yes.
>> So immortality was on the table from the
beginning. Adam sinned. Death came into
creation. And now the Lord has to put a
plan in motion to overcome what Satan
started by lying to Eve. Y'all see that?
He's not going to let a fallen angel
disrupt his plan. So now what? He came
and did what he had to do for us. We're
going to read about it today. But now
it's up to each and every one of us to
do our part to still get the immortality
that was on the table from day one. Do
we see this, brothers and sisters?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Amen.
>> Step down to verse 24. What else it say?
>> So he drove out the manuh
>> and he placed at the east of the garden
of Eden cherubams and a flaming swore
which turned every way to keep the way
of the tree of life. to keep them out of
the Garden of Eden,
>> to keep the way of the tree of life.
>> Oh, you've lost access to immortality.
I'm gonna put these angels right here,
those are the cherubams, to make sure
you understand what you've lost.
>> And I'm not going to give it back until
a certain point in time. Do we
understand that?
>> Yes.
>> That's why when they made the tabernacle
and the temple and all that, when they
made those uh the mercy seat and all
that, on the two ends of that mercy seat
where the Lord was supposed to sit, you
had cherub angels to let you know this
is me right here, even in the garden
from the very beginning. Do we
understand, brothers and sisters? Lord,
>> let's continue. Let's go to Ezekiel
because
man doesn't understand that there's more
than one death.
See, we may not be able to circumvent
the first death. The book says it is
appointed unto man once to die, but then
after that, the judgment. Right.
>> That's right.
>> So, we are trying to be saved from the
second death. The average person in
church don't know that.
This is what we're trying to be saved
from.
Let's read one verse here. Ezekiel the
18th chapter, verse 26. We're going to
see the first and the second death. In
this one verse,
you know, these ministers talking about
living good and all that kind of stuff,
fleecing the people, you know, getting
summer homes and and and Rolls-Royces
and jets and all that. But that's not
what the Lord set this up for.
18 and 26. What did it say, brother?
When a righteous man turneth away from
his righteousness and committh iniquity.
>> So that's somebody that's walking right,
keeping the commandments, but he decides
to turn away from the Lord, right? And
he commits iniquity. That means he
starts sinning against God, right?
>> What does it say?
>> And dieth in him.
>> And dieth in his sin. So he didn't die,
right?
>> Go ahead and read.
>> For his iniquity that he has done.
>> For his iniquity that he had done, shall
he die.
>> Shall he die?
>> How many times you going to die?
>> Read that again. I want this to resonate
with us. Read it again, brother.
>> When a righteous man turneth away from
his righteousness and committeth
iniquity and died in them,
>> he has died a sinner. Go ahead and read.
>> For his iniquity that he has done, shall
he die.
>> Shall he die? Do we see the first and
second death right here, brothers and
sisters?
>> That means that the Lord is going to
raise this person up and judge them and
found them lacking and put them in the
lake of fire. That's what we're trying
to avoid. Do y'all see that?
>> Yes, sir.
>> I just want us to see that. Let's go to
Psalm 69. Let's pursue it a little bit
further, brothers. Psalm chapter 69.
Y'all with me?
>> All right.
We're going to find out why the Lord set
this thing up in the first place. Man
fell from grace from day one. And the
Lord again is on a reconciliation,
recovery, and redemption mission. He had
his part to do, and now we have our part
to do. Brothers and sisters, I want to
make that clear. 69 and verse4, what
does it say? This is Jesus talking. Go
ahead.
>> They that hate me without a cause are
more than the hairs of my head.
>> Uh-huh.
>> They that would destroy me being my
enemies wrongfully are might.
>> Look, he was set free. He didn't do
anything with what the father sent him
to do.
>> Right.
>> But Israel found fault in him. They
said, "Give us barabs."
>> And they had him crucified. He was
supposed to die, but they didn't have
the right mindset. Brothers and sisters.
That's why it says be my enemies
wrongfully they are mighty and what
else?
>> Then I restored that which I took not
away.
>> Oh when they crucified him he restored
that which he took not away. What did he
restore brothers and sisters that he
didn't take away?
>> Our prospects of getting immortality
eternal life brothers. Do we see that?
>> That was an important part of the
process. He had to come and be a sin
offering. Do we understand brothers and
sisters?
>> Yes sir. So when he died, he took us out
of the pit where there's no water. In
other words, we couldn't do anything
about that part. There was no man clean
enough to do. The book said he looked
and saw no man. Talking about the
father. So his arm brought salvation for
him. Right?
>> Skip down, my brother, to verse six and
continue. What does it say?
>> Let not them that wait on thee, oh Lord
God of host, be ashamed for my sake.
>> This is Jesus talking to the father. Go
ahead and read.
>> Let not those that seek thee be
confounded for my sake, oh God of
Israel.
>> Why did he say that? Go ahead. Because
for thy sake I have borne reproach.
>> Oh, you sent me to bear in shame. Go
ahead and read.
>> Shame has covered my face. Uhhuh.
>> I have become a stranger unto my
brotherh
>> and an alien unto my mother's children.
>> Who was the Lord's brethren?
>> Israel.
>> Israel. Who was his mother's children?
>> Israel. Go to Revelation, brothers and
sisters. The Bible says that a woman had
a man child. So Israel is the woman,
right?
>> Yes. And the child was the Lord. Cuz
later on it goes on to say that he was,
you know, after he died and rose, he was
called up to God in his throne. Right?
>> So we know this is talking Jesus. But
when he showed up, they didn't recognize
him because they did not believe in the
scripture. But what did it say?
>> Verse N. For the zeal of thine house
have eaten me up.
>> The zeal of your house have eaten me up.
Paul talked about
all this zeal with no knowledge.
>> Isn't it?
>> Yes, he did.
>> Go and read. and the reproaches of them
that reproach thee are fallen upon me.
>> Oh, so all of this sinfulness and
wickedness and things that they
perpetrating, Lord, we talking man as
well as Israel. It said all of this fell
on me. Ain't that what the book said?
>> Yes, sir.
>> But let's go get confirmation to make
sure we understand this is Jesus and not
David talking. Right. So, Romans the
15th chapter.
Romans 15. Let's confirm that this is
the Lord Jesus talking.
He said, "The reproaches of them that
reproached thee, Father, fell on me. I'm
the one that came and took this woman
for the creation."
>> Praise the Lord.
>> That's what he's saying here.
Romans 15, starting verse one, bro. What
does it say?
>> We then that are strong ought to bear
the infirmities of the weak, and not to
please ourselves.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Let every one of us please his neighbor
for his good to edification.
>> This is the kind of mindset that we
supposed to have, brothers and sisters.
Go ahead and read. For even Christ
pleased not himself.
>> He didn't please himself. But what?
>> But as it is written.
>> As it is what?
>> As is As it is written.
>> As it is written. Go ahead.
>> The reproaches of them that reproach
thee fell on me.
>> And we just read it in Psalm the 69th
chapter. Is that correct, brother?
>> So who was that that said, all of this
fell on my head?
>> Jesus.
>> Jesus. Don't we see that?
>> Now, let's read the definition, my
brother. Yes, sir.
>> Let's read the definition of the word
reconciliation. Brothers and sisters, go
ahead. What does that say?
Reconciliation, noun, the restoration of
friendly relations.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Synonyms, reunited, propitiation,
agreement. Do y'all remember when the
book said that Abraham was the friend of
God?
>> Yes.
>> Well, that was because he obeyed God,
right? When the Lord gave him a
commandment, he didn't hesitate. He
sprung into action. He told him to kill
his son, didn't he?
>> He did.
>> So, to reconcile man back to God is to
restore friendly relations. Because
before Adam sinned, that was the nature
of the relationship between God and man.
Again, he was right there. But once Adam
sinned, it caused that separation.
Brothers and sisters, do we see that?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Now, let's read the definition of the
word recovery because this is what the
Lord is doing. Go ahead and read.
>> Recovery. Now, and return to our normal
state of health, mind, or strength.
>> Uh-huh.
>> The action or process of regaining
possession or control of something
stolen or lost. Oh, man became lost
again, shipwrecked from day one in the
Garden of Eden. So, the Lord is trying
to do his part to recover us. And again,
he employs men. We're going to see that
clearly today to continue the work to
continue the process of recovering and
reconciling man back to them. Read some
synonyms, sir.
>> Synonyms. Retrieval. Uh-huh.
>> Repossession. Uh-huh.
>> Redemption.
>> Retrieval. Repossession. And redemption.
Yes, sir. Keep that word in your back
pocket as we continue, brothers and
sisters. Well, let's go further. Let's
go this time to Romans chapter 5.
Romans chapter 5.
We're going to clearly see what this is
all about. You ask some people, why do
they go to church?
What are you going to get? I don't know.
But the answer is right in the book.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Romans 5 verse one. Go ahead, brother.
What say?
>> Therefore, being justified by faith. We
have peace with God through our Lord
Jesus Christ.
>> Justified by faith, faith without works
is there. So, justified by your
demonstrated works. We have peace with
God through our Lord Jesus Christ
because he's the door. Correct?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead and read. by whom also we have
access by faith into this grace wherein
we stand and rejoice in hope of the
glory of God.
>> Brother Paul be saying mouthfuls
brothers and sisters. Let's break this
down. By whom also we have access by
faith. Question. What if you don't have
faith?
>> Have access.
>> You don't have any access. Right. It
says into this grace where we stand. The
grace is the free gift the shed blood of
Jesus. Right.
>> Yes sir. So you have to believe in him
in order to stand in it. In other words,
to get under his blood. We going to see
that. Go ahead and read, read that part
again, that last end of that verse.
>> And rejoice in hope of the glory of God.
What is this hope, brothers and sisters?
The hope of salvation.
>> It says of the glory of God. Don't y'all
know that we have to be born again? We
have to change glory.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> The book say the glory of the flesh is
one and the glory of the spirits is
another. Right. That's right.
>> Because when we get saved at the time
appointed, we going to change, brother
and sister. We going to still look the
same, but we will no longer have the
same composition. That's what this is
talking about. Now, skip down to verse
six and continue. Let's read a little
bit, brother.
>> All right.
>> For when we were yet without strength,
>> in due time, Christ died for the
ungodly.
>> He died for who?
>> The ungodly.
>> That's all men. When we were yet without
strength, man didn't have any strength
to do anything about the problem. Go
ahead and read. For scarcely for a
righteous man will one die.
>> Yet per adventure for a good man someone
even dared to die.
>> But what?
>> But God commended his love toward us.
And that while we were yet sinners.
>> While we're yet what?
>> Sinners.
>> Sinners. Go ahead and read.
>> Christ died for us.
>> He died for who?
>> Us.
>> For man, brothers and sisters, we were
commandment breakers. Sin is the
transgression of the law. Right.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Said Christ died for us. Go ahead and
read. Much more then being now being now
justified by his blood, we shall be
saved from wrath through him.
>> Being justified by his blood, his shed
blood, we are saved from wrath through.
>> We shall be saved.
>> Oh, this one time.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Future tense. Do y'all see that,
brothers and sisters?
>> We shall be saved from wrath, lake of
fire through him. Go ahead and read.
>> For if when we were enemies, we were
what?
>> Enemies.
>> Enemies. Go ahead and read. We were
reconciled to God by the death of his
son.
>> We were reconciled to God. We were
restored. That friend relationship
>> is now possible again, brothers and
sisters. Do we see it?
>> Yes, sir.
>> When we were enemies, we were reconciled
to God. Go ahead and read.
>> Much more being reconciled, we shall be
saved by his life.
>> He said it again, but go ahead and read,
brother.
>> And not only so, but we also JOIN IN GOD
THROUGH OUR LORD JESUS CHRIST.
>> By whom we have now received the
atonement.
>> Uhuh. You must have read something
wrong, bro. By whom we have now received
salvation.
>> By whom we have now received the
atonement.
>> Oh, and atonement had to be made first,
brothers and sisters.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Now, it's up to us again to work out our
salvation with fear and trembling and
save ourselves.
>> Yes.
>> From this unto our generation. Ain't
that what the apostle say?
>> Yes, sir.
>> We've received the atonement. That was
all important. But let's let's go
further. Let's go to 1 John 2 in the
back of the book. 1 John chapter 2.
An atonement for sin had to be made. Now
we can keep the commandments and live.
Brothers and sisters
John chapter 2,
pick it up at verse one. What does it
say? My little children, these things
run I unto you that you sin not.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And if any man sin, we have an advocate
with the father, Jesus Christ the
righteous. So he's imploring us not to
sin. Don't break the commandments. But
we all fall short some time. He said if
that's the case, we have an advocate
with the father. Don't y'all know when
we pray, we're praying to the father in
the name of Jesus's son. Amen.
>> Because he's the high priest and the
intercessor.
>> He's the one that's taking our
supplication to the father. Do we know
that?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead and read verse two. What you
say, brother? And he is the propitiation
for our sins
>> and not for ours only, but also for THE
SINS OF THE WHOLE WORLD.
>> And I just want to make sure we
understand this point for my Hebrew
brothers out there that only think
Israel is going to be saved.
>> He sacrificed himself for man. Man is
God's business. He just separated our
forefathers and us, right? And made us
his priest. Brothers, we just have to
understand the protocol and the order of
things. Salvation for anybody that turns
to the Lord and is faithful and walks in
his ways. Brothers and sisters,
>> skip down to verse 12. What that say,
sir?
>> I write unto you, little children.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Because your sins are forgiven you for
his name's sake.
>> Oh, your sins are forgiven you for his
name's sake, sir.
>> That's why we got to get under his blood
and hide, brothers and sisters.
>> Yes.
>> Because he is the true lamb of God. We
going to see that as we proceed. But
let's go to 2 Corinthians chapter 5.
2 Corinthians chapter 5 by John.
Are y'all following the story, brothers
and sisters?
>> All right.
We've received the atonement. We are not
saved. Not yet.
>> We got work to do, brothers and sisters.
Yes, sir.
>> 2 Corinthians
chapter 5, let's start at verse 17.
Let's find out a couple things. 2
Corinthians 5 and verse 17. Read,
brother.
>> Therefore, if any man be in Christ, he
is a new creature.
>> Mhm.
>> Old things are passed away.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Behold, all things are become new.
>> And all things are of God, who hath
reconciled us to himself by Jesus
Christ.
>> He's done what?
>> Reconciled us to himself by Jesus
Christ.
>> So, without Jesus shed blood, there's no
reconciliation. Huh?
>> No, sir.
>> Go ahead and read. But what he do? and
had given to us the ministry of
reconciliation.
>> Read that part again, my brother.
>> And had given to US THE MINISTRY OF
RECONCILIATION.
>> The ministry of prosperity, brother.
>> THE MINISTRY OF RECONCILIATION.
>> He's given it to us.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Brothers that stand in the gap like me.
Like I said, brothers and sisters, Jesus
did his part. Now he's employing men to
continue in the work.
>> Come on.
>> To continue in the process of turning
the hearts of the children back to him
and the father. Do we understand what we
read?
>> It's his ministry, but he's given it to
man. Okay, go ahead and read what it
say.
>> To it that God was in Christ,
reconciling the world unto himself.
>> Reconciling Israel TO HIMSELF.
>> RECONCILING THE WORLD UNTO HIMSELF.
>> He my brother,
>> THE WORLD UNTO HIMSELF.
>> JEW, MAN.
>> RECONCILING THE WORLD unto himself.
>> Everybody, brothers and sisters, go
ahead and see.
>> Now beauty and their trespasses unto
themhu
>> and has committed unto us the word of
reconciliation.
>> Oh, we just found out something else.
Not only is there a ministry of
reconciliation, but that ministry has a
particular word that's also called the
word of reconciliation. Right.
>> Yes, sir.
>> We're going to see for instance, there's
only one spirit.
>> Why all these denominations are
different out here?
>> Don't make sense. There's only one body.
>> That's right.
>> Right.
>> Now, let's find out something else.
Read, my brother.
>> Verse 20. Now then, we are ambassadors
for Christ.
>> We are what?
>> Ambassadors for Christ. I don't know
what an ambassador is, brothers and
sisters. A representative
like nations go and send people to other
nations when they have these big
meetings. When they talking about global
affairs, they sent somebody to represent
them, right?
>> Yes.
>> It says, "Now then we are ambassador for
Christ." Go ahead and read
>> as though God did beseech you by us.
>> He beseeched you by us. So you mean I
can tell you some things out of the word
of God that will turn you back to him?
>> Amen.
>> Ain't that what it say?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> We pray you in Christstead. We pray you
in Christstead. We're representing him.
Go ahead and read. He done went back to
heaven. Go ahead and read.
>> Be ye reconciled to God.
>> Be ye reconciled to God. Get that
filthiness out of your mind. All those
sinful things. Learn about his
commandments. Learn about all his ways,
everything that proceed out of his mouth
that he wants you to do and be
reconciled to God. Jesus already brought
you back through the blood. Now you got
to do your part by obeying the word.
Ain't that what we're reading, brother?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> For he has made him to be sin for us.
Uh-huh.
>> Who knew no sin?
>> He was sin free. The book said his mouth
was no God. He was that perfect lamb.
Yes, sir.
>> Without blemish. Go ahead and read.
>> That we might be made the righteousness
of God.
>> Wait a minute. That we might be
>> There's a question, huh?
>> Yes, sir.
>> That part's on you and I brother.
>> We might be made the righteousness of
God. Go ahead.
>> That we may that we might be made the
righteousness of God in him.
>> And right here, I want us to go to the
next chapter. We're going to read in
verse one just to reiterate the point.
I can't stand up here and tell you what
the spirit told me last night. Brothers
and sisters, I got to read this book,
study this book, line up these precepts,
understand these proverbs, and present a
subject or a title so that you can
understand what the Lord want you to
understand out of his word, not what's
in brother Marcus' head.
>> Amen.
>> Y'all understand?
>> Verse one, what it say? We then as
workers together with him,
>> we as what, sir?
>> Workers.
>> Workers together with him. Go ahead and
read.
>> Beseech you also that you receive not
the grace of God in vain.
>> So Paul is warning, don't receive the
grace that shed blood that he freely
gave for all mankind. In other words,
don't take it for nothing. That's right.
>> Because that's what a lot of people are
doing. And they're worried about
everything but what the Lord did to put
us back in a situation so that we can
become immortals in the good side of his
kingdom. And they're worried about
everything otherwise. Brothers and
sisters, do we see what's going on here?
>> Yes.
>> The purpose of the ministry service unto
salvation. We have to work until the
end, whatever that means for you and I.
Whether it's our natural life or until
we're so blessed to live till the Lord
returns a second time. Are we following
it?
>> Yes, sir. Let's read the definition of
that third word, redemption, my brother.
What does that say?
>> Redemption. Now, the action of saving or
being saved from sin, error, or evil.
>> But we've already read some things on
that order, right?
>> Yes, we have.
>> The action of saving or being saved from
sin. That's what Jesus came to do. Go
ahead and read.
>> The action of gaining or regaining
possession of something in exchange for
payment.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Or clearing a debt.
>> Oh, clearing a debt. H. We just read, "I
destroyed that which I took not away."
Right.
>> Yes, sir.
>> So, Adam created a debt and the Lord
cleared it.
>> Praise the Lord.
>> He wiped our sakes clean, brothers and
sisters. We just have to learn again how
to get under his blood.
>> Yes, sir.
>> To hide under that blood and to remain
under that blood. That's what it's
saying. Read those synonyms, bro.
>> Synonyms. Retrieval, recovery, return,
rescue.
>> He's trying to return again, man, back
to God. That's what this is about. First
Peter, the first chapter, brothers and
sisters. First Peter, the first chapter.
Moving right along.
First Peter,
the first chapter.
We going to start at verse three. Then
we going to skip a little. First Peter
1, verse three. What does it say?
Blessed be the God and father of our
Lord Jesus Christ, which according to
his abundant mercy hath begotten us
again into a lively hope by the
resurrection of Jesus Christ from the
dead.
>> Oh, wait a minute, brothers and sisters.
We know he came to die, but then he also
had to rise.
>> Go to Leviticus the 16th chapter. You
can read about the day of atonement,
right?
>> Yes.
>> You had Aaron who was the high priest.
You had the goat that was killed. You
had the goat that was preserved alive.
Okay. And on that live goat's head,
didn't they pray over that goat? Put all
the sins of Israel on that ghost head,
didn't send him away.
>> Yes, sir.
>> That was symbolizing Jesus, brother, and
sisters. So, we have begotten been
begotten to a lively hope. Why is it a
lively hope and not absolute? Because
it's up to you and I.
>> Yes.
>> Right.
>> That's right.
>> Verse four, what did it say? Excuse me.
That was verse 10 of verse three.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Skip to verse five. What did it say?
>> Who are kept by the power of God through
faith unto salvation,
>> ready to be revealed in the last time.
ready to be revealed when
>> in the last time.
>> Oh, not right away.
>> In the last time.
>> Not as soon as you've been baptized and
accept the Lord in your heart.
>> In the last time.
>> In the last time. We're kept by the
power of God. That's through his word
through faith. Believing in that word
unto salvation until the end, brothers
and sisters.
>> Yes.
>> Skip down to verse n. What that say?
>> Receiving the end of your faith.
>> Receiving the end of your faith. In
other words, once you have walked this
walk down and it's all said and done,
then what, brother?
>> Even the salvation of your soul.
>> Oh, then that's where you get payday.
The end of your faith is the salvation
of your souls. Are we following,
brothers and sisters?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Skip down to 17. What it say?
>> And if you call on the father, who
without respect of persons judgeth
according to every man's work.
>> Judge according to what, my brother?
>> To every man's work.
>> Wait a minute. I thought we didn't have
to do any works. Don't they preach that
on Sunday?
>> That's what they say.
>> You don't have to keep the law. The Lord
did it all. What did he say? Go ahead
and read.
>> Pass the time of your souljourneying
here in fear.
>> Uh-huh.
>> For as much as ye know that ye were not
redeemed with corruptible things.
>> You were not redeemed with corruptible
things, but what?
>> As silver and gold from your vain
conversation received by tradition from
your fathers. Oh, so you can receive
tradition from your fathers.
>> That's for nothing. That's what vain is,
right?
>> Yes, sir.
>> But what were we redeemed with, my
brother? Read verse 19.
>> But with the precious blood of Christ,
>> as of a lamb without blemish and without
spot.
>> So his death was integral in this
process. Brothers and sisters, do we see
this? Yes,
>> sir.
>> It says as of the precious blood of
Christ, as of a lamb without blemish and
without spot. So now let's go to Exodus
12. Let's take a look at the Passover
because the world is keeping communion.
>> Yes.
>> But the book said keep the Passover once
a year at its prescribed time.
>> You keeping communion however many times
you want.
You going to forget when we supposed to
do the bread and the wine. That's right.
Like brother said, you celebrate your
birthday every month. Sooner or later,
you're going to forget when you was
born.
>> But Exodus 12, let's start reading, my
brother, at verse number three. Then
we're going to skip Exodus 12
and three. What does it say? speak ye
unto all the congregation of Israel,
saying, in the 10th day of this month,
they shall take to them every man a lamb
according to the house of their fathers,
a lamb for an house. So this is Israel
in Egypt. He said, tell them on this
particular day, right, to get them a
lamb for an house. Correct?
>> That's right.
>> Skip down to verse 5 and continue.
>> Your lamb shall be without blemish.
>> Uhhuh. a male of the first year, you
shall take it out from the sheep or from
the goats.
>> So this lamb had to be perfect. It had
to be a male. It had to be the firstborn
of its mother. And he said, "Take it out
from the sheep and from the goat."
I wonder who this is prophesying about.
So uh skip down, my brother. No, keep
reading verse six. What does it say?
>> And ye shall keep it up until the 14th
day OF THE SAME MONTH.
>> THE 14th day of the month. Go ahead and
read. And the whole assembly of the
congregation of Israel shall kill it in
the evening.
>> The whole assembly of the congregation
of Israel shall kill it in the evening.
H again, who called for Jesus's death?
Because when I was growing up, I thought
the Romans killed Jesus.
>> They had this little book when I was in
Sunday school. The soldier standing up
under the cross and he was up there, the
white Jesus with the blonde hair, blue
eyes. They didn't have one Israelite on
the pictures. So I thought it was the
Romans that did it. But the whole
congregation of the Israel killed him
again. They called for his death. They
said, "Give us Barabus of thee, brothers
and sisters."
>> But let's see what they going to do with
this land. Go ahead and read
>> verse seven. And they shall take of the
blood.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And strike it on the two side posts and
on the UPPER DOORPOST OF THE houses
wherein they shall eat.
>> Now, let's find out why he instructed
them to do this. Okay, let's get right
down to it. Skip down to verse 12. We're
talking about the Passover when it was
first instituted in Egypt.
>> Verse 12, what it say?
>> FOR I WILL PASS THROUGH THE LAND OF
EGYPT this night AND WILL SMITE ALL THE
FIRSTBORN IN THE LAND OF EGYPT, both man
and beast, AND AGAINST ALL THE GODS OF
EGYPT. I WILL EXECUTE JUDGMENT. I am the
Lord.
>> So the Lord said, "Do this because I'm
about to send that death angel through
there toh smite all the firstborn in the
land. Whether it's a man or a beast, I'm
about to do some killing." Yes, sir.
>> I'm going TO SHOW Y'ALL I'M THE LORD.
I'M GOD. OKAY. What it say?
>> And the blood shall be to you for a
token upon the houses where you are.
>> Wait a minute. A token. A token of what,
brothers and sisters?
>> Your faith.
>> Your faith. Why? Because I told you to
do it. I know you have faith in me if
you DO WHAT I SAY.
>> That's right.
>> IF I TELL YOU TO DO SOMETHING, you sit
around twing your thumbs and I come back
to you and you say, "Yeah, I got faith
in you, Lord. I got faith in you, Lord."
But you haven't done anything. Have you
demonstrated that you have faith in me?
>> Not at all.
>> Not at all. So he said, "The blood shall
be to you for a token upon the house
where you are." Because that individual
did what I told him to do. But go ahead
and read what it say.
>> AND WHEN I SEE THE BLOOD,
>> UHUH. when I see the righteous
individual, sir.
>> And when I see the blood,
>> just the Hebrew Israelites in the land.
>> I see the blood. I'm not looking at
who's at the house. That's right.
>> Okay. Spiritually, brothers and sisters,
I'm not looking at what you used to be.
If you get yourself under my blood, I'm
just going to look at the fact that you
obeyed me and that you walking with me.
Amen.
>> Not going to look at the old sinful
person you used to be.
>> Y'all understand what we reading here.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> I will pass over you.
>> I will pass over you. That's where the
term literally comes from. Oh, the blood
is on the house. Don't go in there. Go
to the next house. Check it out. Go
ahead and read. And the plague SHALL NOT
BE UPON YOU TO DESTROY YOU when I smite
the land of Egypt.
>> And that was the plague of death. And on
the spiritual side, it's also the plague
of death. And we talking about what,
brother and sister?
>> The second death,
eternal damnation in the lake of fire.
Are we following?
>> So
we read that Jesus was a lamb without
spot and without blemish. Correct?
That's right.
>> Let's go to 1 Corinthians 5. Let's see
if we can get a correlation here. 1
Corinthians chapter 5,
the book say without the shedding of
blood there is no remission.
Y'all understand that if Jesus didn't
come and die, we just cut off.
>> That's right.
>> That's the whole point.
Notice everything starts with the
Passover.
Then come all the feasts and the high
day.
>> Yes, sir.
>> He had to come and die first.
1 Corinthians the 5th chapter
start at verse six. My brother, wait a
second.
>> Your glorying is not good.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Know ye not that a little leth the whole
lump?
>> So spiritually, brothers and sisters,
what he's saying is a little sin
>> that breeds more and more sin.
>> Oh, I did that. I got away with it.
Maybe I can do a little bit of this and
that before you know it. You kne deep in
it.
>> That's what he's saying. A little
leavening leaven the whole lump. But go
ahead and read what it say.
>> Purge out therefore the older.
>> Get all them old sinful thoughts and
ways out your mind. Why?
>> That ye may be a new one.
>> That you may be a new lump, a new
creature. Did we read that?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> As you are unleavened.
>> As you are what?
>> Unleavened.
Spiritually you are sin free. How did
you get that way? Christ purged you with
his blood.
>> Yes.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> For even Christ our Passover is
sacrificed for us.
>> Read that again, brother. For even
Christ our Passover is sacrificed for
us.
>> So who was that that lamb that was
sacrificed starting in Egypt? Who was
that representing brothers and sisters?
>> Only Jesus.
>> Jesus. That was foreshadowing Jesus. He
was going to come and shed his blood.
Again, if you get under it, you hide
under the blood of the real lamb. Just
like the people in Egypt, the children
of Israel hid under the blood of that
lamb they put over their doorpost, then
you will be preserved alive. the death
angel will not come in or that plague of
death will not take hold of you and I.
That's what he's saying here, brothers
and sisters. Y'all understand what we're
reading?
>> Yes.
>> Now, let's go back to Ezekiel this time,
chapter 36. Y'all with me?
>> All right. Ezekiel chapter 36.
We're just showing you that in order for
us to be reconciled, redeemed, and
recovered, Jesus had to come and die,
shed his blood for remission of sins,
and then he had to rise again on the
third day so that he could put the sins
of man on his head and carry them away
and make that atonement for us.
>> Amen.
>> Now, we can keep the commandments and
live and get the immortality that was on
the table that we lost access to from
day one. Brothers and sisters, do we see
that? Yes, sir.
>> All right. Ezekiel 36.
>> So once you get under the blood,
right? Once you put yourself under the
blood of the lamb, under under the
Passover, even Jesus. Now let's see what
you have to deal with.
Verse 24, 36 and 24. What does it say?
>> For I will take you from among the
heathen
>> and gather you out of all countries and
will bring you into your own land.
>> So this is future. This is what the Lord
is going to do with Israel, brothers and
sisters. But I want to show y'all
something. Let's see what he going to do
once he gather them and bring them into
their own land. What it say?
>> Then will I SPRINKLE CLEAN WATER UPON
you
>> and ye shall be clean?
>> Wait a minute. I'm going to sprinkle
clean water. Is he going to take them to
the river and dip them in the river and
give them a bath?
>> Is that what he talking about, BROTHERS
AND SISTERS?
>> OH, I will sprinkle clean water on you
and you shall be clean. This is the
water of the word, brothers and sisters.
>> Yes. the same old word that he been
sending down from day one. Start at 25
again, brother.
>> Then will I SPRINKLE CLEAN WATER UPON
YOU, and you shall be clean from all
your filthy and from all your idols will
I cleanse you.
>> Said you're not going to be serving no
pagan gods and bowing down to wood and
stone no more.
>> You going to serve me and only me. Let's
see what else he say.
>> A new heart also will I GIVE YOU.
>> A NEW WHAT?
>> A new heart also will I give you.
>> You going to take this out of my chest
and put something else there, brother,
sister?
>> No. Now, what is he talking about?
>> A new mind,
>> yes.
>> One that's obedient and not hard-hearted
and stiff neck.
>> He said, "A new heart will also I give
you." Go ahead.
>> And a new spirit will I put within you.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And I will take away,
>> excuse me, and I will TAKE AWAY THE
STONY HEART out of your flesh.
>> And I will give you an heart of flesh.
>> I will give you a heart that's willing
to obey my commandments.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> And I WILL PUT MY SPIRIT WITHIN YOU. And
I will put my spirit within you, my word
within you, brothers and sisters. And
once that word is in you, what's going
to happen? Go ahead and read.
>> And cause YOU TO WALK IN MY STATUTES.
>> OH, CAUSE YOU to walk in my statute. So
once we receive the word, we got to do
something.
>> Don't we see that?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead, read.
>> And you shall keep my judgments
>> and do them.
>> And you shall keep my judgments and do
them. So much for we don't have to do
any work. This is future, brothers and
sisters. This is when the Lord return.
He still expect you to obey his voice
and keep his commandments. Isn't that
what we mean?
>> Go ahead, brother.
>> And ye shall dwell in the land that I
gave to your father. And ye shall be my
people, and I will be your God.
>> And that's all predicated on obeying his
word. Don't we see that, brothers and
sisters?
>> Now, let's get into it. That was the
foundation. But now, let's get into some
particulars. Okay?
>> Yes.
>> Let's go to Ephesians, the fourth
chapter. Ephesians chapter 4.
Ephesians chapter 4.
Let's start at verse one. Let's point
some things out, brother. Ephesians 4:1.
Now go ahead and read what he say.
>> I therefore the prisoner of the Lord
beseech you that you are worthy of the
vocation wherewith you are called.
>> You don't see the language Paul is using
vocation. That's like a job or some type
of career path for work. Right.
>> That's right. Yes, sir.
>> So we've been called to a particular
walk. But he said walk worthy of it.
Right.
>> That's right.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> With all loneliness and meekness, with
longsuffering, forbearing one another in
love.
>> Uhhuh. endeavoring to keep the unity of
the spirit in the bond of peace.
>> You all see the fruits of the spirit
kind of popping up right here. Yes, sir.
>> Because that's the mindset servants of
God is supposed to have and things we
supposed to have on display at all time.
It say endeavor to keep the unity of the
spirit. That's that word in the bond of
peace. Read my brother.
>> Verse four. There is one body.
>> How many?
>> One body.
>> One body. Go ahead and read.
>> And one spirit.
>> How many spirits?
>> One.
>> Go ahead. Even as you ARE CALLED IN ONE
HOPE of your call.
>> That one body is the body of Christ.
That one spirit is the word that he sent
down. And the one hope of your calling
is the hope that you can work out your
salvation and be saved at the time
appointed. Don't Jesus say, "My behold,
my reward is with me."
>> With me?
>> Yes.
>> Right.
>> That's right.
>> That when he come, right?
>> Free.
>> One Lord, one faith, one baptism.
>> One Lord Jesus. One faith. Believing in
him, his name, his word, his blood, his
resurrection, all that. and getting
baptized in his name because he is the
high priest and the intercessor. Go
ahead and read.
>> One God and father of all
>> who is above all and through all and in
you all.
>> This is all about reconciling man back
to the father.
>> Okay, that's what this is all about
brothers and sisters. Skip down to verse
10. Let's continue. What does it say?
>> He that descended is the same also that
descended up far above all heavens.
>> What we talking about, brothers and
sisters? That's Jesus, right? He the one
that came down from heaven and went
back. Go ahead, read.
>> That he might fill all things.
>> Now, let's see what he did. We know that
this is Jesus, right?
>> Yes.
>> Let's see what he did. Go ahead and
read.
>> And he gave some apostles.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And some prophets and some evangelists
>> and some pastors and teachers.
>> Now, wait a minute. Now, we read this
that this is the the ministry of Jesus.
It's the ministry of reconciliation that
he gave to us. And he also gave us the
word of reconciliation. But right here,
we just read, he gave apostles at some
point in time. He gave prophets at some
point in time, evangelists, pastors, and
teachers. I don't care what the title
is, brothers and sisters. They're
supposed to all be in line with him
because he gave these brothers.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Do we see that?
>> Let's see why. We're going to read these
three particular points. We're going to
deal with them for the remainder of the
lesson. Why did he give you prophets,
man? apostle because this spans many
generations. Right.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Why did he do that? Read, brother.
>> For the perfecting of the saints.
>> That's one reason.
>> For the work of the ministry.
>> That's another reason.
>> For the edifying of the body of Christ.
>> The third reason. Y'all see that,
brothers and sisters? For the perfecting
of the saints. For the work of the
ministry. For the edifying of the body
of Christ. This is what the purpose of
him giving these individuals spanning
all these generations was for. these
particular things. Go ahead and read
>> verse 13.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Till we all come in the unity of the
faith.
faith. We shouldn't be all walking all
over the place. The book of Amos says,
"Can two walk together except they be
agree." What's the answer?
>> No. How you going to walk with the Lord
if you say, "Thus said the Lord, do this
and that." You way over here.
>> Are you walked with him?
>> Just because you calling on his name?
>> No. Go ahead. Three.
>> And of the knowledge of the Son of God.
>> Unto what, brother? unto a perfect man.
>> unto a perfect man. Uh-huh.
>> Unto the measure of the stature of the
fullness of Christ.
>> Do we understand what we just read,
brothers and sisters? Unto a perfect
man. Unto the measure of the stature of
the fullness of Christ. Nobody in here
is perfect. I was going to say if we
perfect, raise your hand. But I ain't
going to ask nobody.
>> Okay. But it says unto the measure of
the stature of the fullness of Christ.
Jesus came down right in the flesh. He
was a man, right? He lived at about 30.
He got baptized when he got anointed and
became the Christ. A lot of people don't
understand that he was not always the
anointed one. That happened at his
baptism. Then he ministered for three
and a half years and he got cut off in
the middle of that week. Okay? He was
put in the grave for three days and
three nights. And on the third day he
rose. I have a question for y'all. When
he came out the grave, was he the same
way that he was when he went in?
>> No. He was born again.
>> Yes.
>> He was the firstborn from the dead.
Okay. So, this is letting us know right
here what our potential is. So, your
minister, your pastor, your preacher,
your teacher is supposed to be
perfecting you, working in this
ministry, and edifying you so that you
can be just like Jesus. when he came out
to pray. Do we see that, brothers and
sisters?
>> Yes, sir.
>> The purpose of the ministry, service
unto salvation. That's what this is all
about. Let's bring you another
definition, my brother.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Read the definition of the word
perfecting for me.
>> Perfecting.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Third, the process of making something
completely free from faults or defects.
>> Uh-huh.
>> The process of bringing to completion to
finish.
>> Because no man sinned against God, he
found fault with us. Right.
>> Yeah. So we were no longer perfect in
his eyes. We were we were defective. So
it says the process of bringing to
completion to finish.
He created us brothers and sisters with
the potential to become just like them.
The book says that everything else was
created after what? His kind.
>> But when it came to us, it was image and
likeness. Right?
>> With the potential to become after their
kind. Do we see that? So, one of the
things we just read about was the
perfecting of the saints. Let's pursue
that. Let's see what this looks like.
But first and foremost, we have to
identify what a saint is according to
the scripture. Because I watch these
shows and stuff sometimes, you know, the
minister be up there talking, then all
the saints in the house say, "Amen."
Right? Everybody's the same.
>> You know, that bothers me.
>> Yes. Because I'm truly trying to
maintain my status, brother.
>> That's right.
>> That's a saint. Okay. Yes, sir.
>> Well, let's read what the biblical
definition of a saint is. Revelation
14. We're going to read one verse,
brothers and sisters, because that's the
reason he gave these men. Again, I don't
care what the title is. You're a
spiritual leader. This is the business
that you're supposed to be about.
You know,
I'm not concerned about making no money
preaching, okay? I'm doing this for
salvation, brothers and sisters.
>> Amen.
>> All right. The ministers of the Israel
of God don't get paid. We are working
for salvation.
>> Revelation 14 and verse 12. What did it
say, bro?
>> Here is the patience of the saints.
>> Here is the patience of the saints. Go
ahead and read.
>> Here are they that keep the commandments
of God
>> and what else?
>> And the faith of Jesus.
>> We just read two qualifying conditions,
didn't we?
>> Yes, sir. The saints keep the
commandments of God and the faith of
Jesus. So the first part of that just
knocks a whole lot of folks out the box,
right?
>> Yeah.
>> Cuz they don't believe. They say we
don't have to deal with the law anymore.
They call brothers and sisters like you
and I legalists, which I don't mind.
What's wrong with being legal? Like
brother Pooie say, right? So they don't
keep the commandments, right? And it
also said the faith of Jesus. But
there's a problem a lot of people don't
know. There's another Jesus that's being
preached in the world.
>> So which one are you following? Are you
following the one that you can read
about out of the pages of the book that
says keep the Sabbath the seventh day of
the week or the one that said keep
Sunday the first day of the week? Are
you reading about the one or believing
in the one got faith in the one that
tell you to keep the Passover and the
holidays or are you dealing with the one
that keep Christmas? You know the one
that was born on December the 25th
>> and the one that rose early
on Easter Sunday morning.
>> Come on y'all.
So I can conclude based on what we just
read that a whole lot of people are
disqualified for being called a saint.
Right.
>> That's right.
>> Yeah. That's right.
>> Okay. So, but we're talking about the
perfecting of those who are keeping
God's commandments and who believe in
truly living in God. Let's look and see
what this process entail. Let's go to
Proverbs the 4th chapter. Look, don't be
calling, brother. Plus, Mark like to
have a little fun sometime. Okay? Don't
be I don't want to get no phone call.
I'll be cautious when I get back.
>> Proverbs 4.
Let's start at verse one. Proverbs 4 and
one. What does it say?
>> Hear ye children the instruction of a
father.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And attend to know understanding.
>> Attend to know understanding. Go ahead.
>> For I give you good doctrine. I give you
good doctrine, sound doctrine. Go ahead.
>> Forsake you not my law.
>> Forsake not what?
>> My law.
>> Oh, so upon that good doctrine, that
sound doctrine is the commandments.
>> Yes, it is.
>> Oh, okay.
Skip down to verse four and continue. My
brother,
>> he taught me also and said unto me,
>> Uhhuh.
>> Let thine heart retain my words.
>> Keep my words in your mind. What?
>> Keep my commandments and live.
>> Keep my commandments and live. Not only
now in the temporal but as we stated
earlier forever
>> the commandments are ordained to eternal
life. That's what we have to deal with.
Didn't we read here's the places of the
saints? Yes, sir.
>> You know they that keep the commandments
of God and the faith of Jesus. That's
right.
>> He said keep my commandments and live.
>> Go ahead, brother.
>> Get wisdom.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Get understanding. Forget it not.
>> Neither decline from the words of my
mouth.
>> Do not turn to the left or the right. Go
ahead and read.
>> FORSAKE HER NOT. AND SHE SHALL PRESERVE
THEE.
>> UHHUH.
>> Love her and she shall keep thee.
>> So this is personification. This is
talking about wisdom, right?
>> And intangible or untangible. Right? But
the Lord has given these things, these
attributes so we can understand.
It says, "Get wisdom and understanding.
Forget it not, neither decline from the
words of my mouth." Read verse six.
>> Forsake her not
>> and she shall preserve thee.
>> Love her and she shall keep you.
>> Go ahead and read. Pay attention. Wisdom
is the principle thing.
>> Wisdom is the main thing. Go ahead and
read.
>> Therefore, get wisdom.
>> And with all thy getting.
>> With all thy getting, do what, brother?
>> Get understanding.
>> Oh, with all your getting, get
understanding.
I know people that's reading the book
and quoting scripture and all this and
they're coming to the wrong conclusion
because they're not doing what the Bible
says. They're not putting precept on
precept line on line. They're not going
here little and there a little so that
they can get the proper understanding.
This book is like a big jigsaw puzzle,
brothers and sisters. You got to put
these pieces together so that the
picture becomes clearer and clear.
That's why we deal with one subject at a
time.
>> Amen.
>> With all your getting, get
understanding. Read, brother.
>> Exalt her and she shall promote thee.
>> Exalt wisdom and she shall promote thee.
>> We don't have everything we we going to
get already. What kind of promotion is
man looking for? What kind of
graduation? Like brother Jules said, we
looking for from man to God, brother,
and sister. Do y'all see that? Yes, sir.
>> But you got to be wise. Eve made a
mistake. She thought the tree and
knowledge of good and evil was going to
make her wise. Didn't we read that?
>> Yes, sir. We did.
>> But we need the wisdom of the Lord. Go
ahead and read.
>> She shall bring thee to honor when thou
dost embrace her.
>> What else?
>> She shall give she Excuse me.
>> She shall give to thine head an ornament
of grace.
>> What else?
>> A CROWN OF GLORY SHALL SHE DELIVER to
thee. Oh, a crown of glory shall you
deliver to thee?
>> Who was that that was talking about a
crown was laid up for them?
>> Paul the apostle, right?
>> Yes, sir.
>> But he said it wasn't just for him only.
Just cuz he was the apostle.
>> He said for who else?
>> All those that love Jesus's appearing.
>> So if we endure, you and I can say the
same thing. But we got to keep the
faith. But we have to understand the the
the purpose of knowledge, wisdom, and
understanding, brothers and sisters.
That's what's going to allow us to get
that crown at the time of recording. Do
we see that, brothers and sisters?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Let's go to Luke 13.
Let's make sure we understand
what being perfect
is all about because it says perfecting
of the saints. That's a process we read,
right?
>> Mhm. That's right.
>> We're trying to get to somewhere at the
end of the line that we are definitely
not at right now.
Luke 13.
This is when
some of these Pharisees came up on the
Lord. You know, they trying to give him
an ammonition. They didn't really care
for him too much. They was always trying
to get him caught up anyway. That's
right.
>> They going to come in the spirit of
trying to help him out, y'all.
>> Right. Let's see what it say. Luke 13
and 31. What it say, brother?
>> The same day there came certain of the
Pharisees, saying unto him,
>> Uhhuh. Get thee out AND THE BARN HITS
FOR HERA WILL KILL ME.
>> They say, "Man, you better book. You
better get out of town because this king
Herod is going to kill you. He going to
take you out." They wasn't concerned
about that.
You know, they felt like he was taking
that shine and all that stuff anyway.
They said, "Hey man, you better go cuz
they're not going to kill you, right?
Let's see what he said."
>> And he said unto them,
>> Uhhuh.
>> "Go ye and tell their fuckhu,
>> Behold, I cast out devils."
>> Uhhuh. And I do cures today and
tomorrow. And the third day I shall be
perfected.
>> And the third day I shall be what?
>> Perfected.
>> Perfected. Again, what happened on the
third day when he rose, brothers and
sisters?
>> He was no longer the son of man, but he
was the son of God. And we going to see
what's he was born again. Again, he had
received the change. Isn't that correct?
>> That's right. Correct. So when it talks
about the perfecting of the saints, we
read until the measure of the statute of
the fullness of Christ, all this is
about us being able to get into that
same position at the time appointed,
brothers and sisters. Right? So we don't
we see that being perfect is having that
glorified spiritual body.
>> That's what he's talking about. So let's
prove it. Let's go to Romans the first
chapter. Let's take a look at when he
rose. Romans 1.
Romans chapter 1.
>> Romans 1. Let's pick it up at verse one.
Brothers and sisters, go ahead and read.
>> Paul, a servant of Jesus Christ, called
to be an apostle, separated unto the
gospel of God,
>> WHICH HE HAD PROMISED BEFORE BY HIS
PROPHETS IN THE holy scripture.
>> Uhhuh. concerning his son Jesus Christ
our Lord which was made of the seed of
David according to the flesh.
>> Oh, he was made of the seed of David
according to the flesh. No wonder those
folks who said uh uh thou son of of
David save now Hosanna in the highest
son
>> because the Lord promised David that his
seed he was going to raise up to sit up
on his throne. Right. Yes sir. Before
him forever. So according to the flesh,
he was of the lineage of David. That's
why he's the lion of the tribe of Judah.
That's right.
>> Right. But go ahead and read what verse
four say, brother.
>> And declared to be the son of God with
power.
>> And declared to be the what, sir?
>> The son of God with what power?
>> With power.
>> See, we sons and daughters of God right
now be led by the spirit. But we ain't
got that type of power. Remember once
the Lord rose, he did something he had
never done before. Remember the apostles
were kind of scared. They was in the
room with the doors locked and all that.
>> Yes, sir.
>> And Jesus popped up in the middle of him
and said, "Peace be unto you."
>> Yes.
>> He had done anything like that before,
but his glory was changed. He was a
spirit being again. So what is going to
do? He walked right through the wall.
But he was declared to be the son of God
with power. Let's see how, brother. Go
ahead. Read.
>> According to the spirit of holiness by
the resurrection from the dead.
>> Oh,
that's the other thing. You become a son
or daughter of God with power if you
come up in the first resurrection.
>> That's right.
>> Right. Or if you stand in that line, the
white drum judgment and he makes the
cut.
>> You become a son of God with power. But
that's by way of the resurrection, not a
day before. Do we see that?
>> Yes.
>> Jesus was the son of God for sure, but
he was the son of God with power after
he rose. Do we see that, brothers and
sisters? Yes, sir.
>> The measure and stature of the fullness
of Christ. Hebrews chapter 2, brothers
and sisters, let's move right along.
Hebrews chapter 2.
Y'all all right?
>> Praise God. Praise the Lord.
Hebrews chapter 2.
We going to read verse one. Then we're
going to skip down Hebrews 2
and verse one. When you get it, my
brother, go ahead and read that.
Therefore, we ought to give the more
earnest heed to the things which we have
heard.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Lest at any time we should let them
slip.
>> In other words, once you receive that
word, hold fast to it. Don't let it go,
brothers and sisters. That's what he's
saying. Skip down to verse five to
continue, brother. Let's pay attention,
y'all. What it say?
>> For unto the angels hath he not put in
subjection the world to come, whereof we
speak.
>> So Paul is talking about future tense.
He said, "Unto the angels, he have not
put in subjection the world to come."
So, we're talking about
when the resurrection takes place,
right?
>> That's right.
>> He has not put that in the charge of the
angel. But what?
>> But one in a certain place testify,
saying, "What is man that thou are
mindful of him?"
>> Uhhuh.
>> Or the son of man that thou visitest
him. What is important about this man
Lord that you thinking about him in this
manner or why are you even visiting him?
Why you come down? Why you been sending
all these prophets and stuff? Why you
come and pick apostles to send out to
this man? Go ahead and read.
>> Thou make him a little lower than the
angels.
>> Flesh and blood. Go ahead and read.
>> Thou crownest him with glory and honor.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And then it set him over the works of
thy hands.
>> We can read that right at the beginning
of the book. Right.
>> Yes, sir. Out of all the things that the
Lord created, he gave man that
preeminence. Correct?
>> That's right.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> Thou has put all things in in subjection
under his feet.
>> Uhhuh.
>> For in that he put all the subjection
under him. He left nothing that was not
put under him.
>> So he gave him dominion over everything.
Right.
>> But check this out, brothers and
sisters. What it say?
>> But now we see not yet all things put
under him.
>> Oh, but now we see not yet all things
put under him. Because that's for a time
appointed. The Bible speaks of things
that are not as though they were. And he
called the end from the beginning. Then
sir, if you understand this word, you
know what man is going to be. All those
that make the cut, brothers and sisters.
Right. But let's see what about our Lord
and Savior Jesus Christ. What it say?
>> Verse N. But we see Jesus who was made a
little lower than the angels for the
suffering of death.
>> Oh, he became what his creation was. He
became flesh and blood too.
>> Huh, son? And it says, "For the
suffering of death." That's why he came.
Go ahead and read.
>> Crowned with glory and honor that he by
the grace of God should taste death for
every man.
>> Oh, so he tasted death so we wouldn't
have to taste the second death.
>> Amen.
>> That makes sense. Don't brothers and
sisters,
>> keep reading, brother. What it say?
>> For it became him. For whom are all
things and by whom are all things?
>> So he created everything. He did.
>> It was the son, brothers and sist. Some
people say the father was the father.
No, he said the son to do all the heavy
lifting. Go ahead. Three.
>> And bringing many sons unto glory.
>> And bringing what?
>> Many sons unto glory.
>> Bringing many sons and daughters unto
glory.
Right. Unto the point in time where you
going to get that glorified spiritual
body with the same composition that the
father and Jesus have right now. Do we
understand when we read, brothers and
sisters?
>> Come on. Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> To make the CAPTAIN OF THIS SALVATION
perfect through suffering.
>> Pay attention. Read verse 11. What it
say?
>> For both he that sanctifith Uhuh.
>> and they who are sanctified are all of
one.
>> Wait a minute. This is talking the Lord,
right? Jesus.
>> That's right.
>> He the one that sanctifies us. It says
both he that sanctifies and they who are
sanctified. Talking about all of us.
We're all one.
>> All are one.
>> But y'all understand the body is Jesus.
He's the head or the chief cornerstone.
Right.
>> Yes.
>> But we are also bricks in this building.
Brothers and sisters, we're all part of
the same house. So why not be able to
get to the point we can get the same
thing he got when he rose?
>> Doesn't that make sense?
>> It does.
>> Start at verse 11 again. What it say?
>> For both he that sanctifith and they who
are sanctifier are all of one.
>> Uhhuh.
>> For which cause he is not ashamed to
call them brethren.
>> He's not ashamed to call them what?
Brethren.
>> Brethren. And I'm talking about in the
truest and fullest sense.
>> Yes, sir.
>> But it starts right here, brother and
sister. Remember when those folks told
Jesus that his family was looking for
him? Said, "Your your mother and your
brother want to talk to you, Lord?" And
he said, "Who is my my mother? Who is my
brother?" And he turned to his
disciples, the people that followed him,
the people who had faith in him, and
said, "Behold, my mother and my brother,
those that do the will of my father,
that's who my mother and brother is."
You all understand? So it went, you
know, transcended the physical and went
to the spiritual. So it says he's not
ashamed to call them brethren because
he's trying to make us like him. Are we
following the story? Yes, sir.
>> Read the next verse. What does it say?
>> Verse 12. Saying, I will declare THY
NAME UNTO MY BRETHREN.
>> I WILL declare thy name unto my
brethren. Go ahead.
>> In the midst of the church WILL I SING
PRAISE UNTO THEE.
>> And and a lot of these brothers have a
problem with the name. But the book say
in Malachi from the rising of the sun to
the going down in the same my name shall
be great among the Gentiles also the
heir.
>> Right.
>> That's right.
>> And from what I understand that name is
Jesus. Because you can go talking about
Yahwa Yehud and all this other stuff and
people going to look at you like you
crazy. But when you say Jesus, you going
to get some respect. Am I right?
>> I making this up now. Amen.
>> They say my name. I'm going to declare
thy name. Right.
>> That's right.
>> That's all I want to hear.
>> Let's go to Hebrews the first chapter.
back up to Hebrews the first chapter.
Let's pursue further. Again, we're
talking about this perfection.
Like I said, these guys be standing up
in these pull pits and these churches
talking about everything but what thus
sayeth the Lord, y'all.
Hebrews the first chapter. Let's start
reading at verse 10. Pay attention cuz
we just read about the angels will not
be, you know, controlling the world to
come. Right. That's right. Verse 10,
what does it say?
>> And thou, Lord, in the beginning has
laid the foundation of the earthh, and
the heavens are the works of thine
hands.
>> That's just confirmation. That's talking
Jesus. Go ahead, read.
>> They shall perish, but thou remainest.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And they all shall wax old as such a
gar.
>> Uh-huh. He's going to rework everything.
Go ahead and read.
>> And as the vest shalt thou fold them up,
>> and they shall be changed.
>> Go ahead.
>> But thou art the same, and thy year
shall not fail.
>> Go ahead. BUT TO WHICH of the angels
said he at any time sit on my right hand
until I make thine enemies thy foottool?
>> Which one brothers and sisters?
>> Not one. Because they are ministering or
serving spirits. We going to see that in
a minute. He only said this to Jesus. Go
to Psalm 110.
Sit on my right hand until I make thy
enemies thy foottool. That's after he
rose and went back to heaven. He sat
down on the right hand of the father and
he's sitting there until he tell him to
get up and go rule in the midst of your
enemies, son.
>> Right?
>> But I want us to pay attention to
something. This is really why we came
here. Read verse 14. What does it say,
bro?
>> Are they not all ministering spirits?
>> Are they not what?
>> All ministering spirits.
>> All ministering spirits. I don't care if
they fallen angels or holy angels. They
are ministering spirits. Do y'all know
Satan's work for God?
He can't do anything without the Lord's
permission is active for passive will.
Do we know that?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Are they not all ministering spirit? But
what brothers
>> sent forth to minister for them who
shall be heirs of salvation?
>> Brothers and sisters, do we understand
what we just read here?
Are they not all ministering spirits?
Sent forth to minister for them who
shall be hes of salvation. Who we
talking, brothers and sisters?
>> You and I, if we make the cut,
>> right?
>> We will have charge over angels. We'll
be able to tell them what to do because
we'll no longer be man. Who will we be?
God.
>> God at this time. Do y'all understand?
Let's pursue a little further. 1
Corinthians the 15th chapter.
1 Corinthians 15.
Let's look at it further, brothers and
sisters.
Let's look at the order of things.
Let's start at verse 20. 1 Corinthians
15 and 20. What does it say?
>> But now is Christ risen from the dead
and become the first fruits of them that
slept. Oh, we're coming up on Pentecost.
That's what the Pentecost is all about,
brothers and sisters. He's the first
fruits of them. In other words, that
died and rose from among men. He is the
first of the first fruits. That's why
after so much time after seven Sabbaths
are complete on that next day, which
would be day number 50, because 7 * 7 is
49, right? That's right.
>> One more day makes 50. That's what
Pentecost means. Then that second set of
first fruit comes up that represents
everybody out of the realm of man that's
going to make the cut y'all. We about to
deal with that coming up. But go ahead
and read.
>> For since by man came deathhu
>> by man came also the resurrection of the
dead.
>> Uhhuh.
>> For as in Adam all died.
>> How many?
>> All died.
>> In Adam all died. Didn't the Lord said,
"Dust thou art and unto doubt shalt thou
return?"
>> Yes, sir.
>> Isn't man still died even in this
generation?
>> They all go ahead and read. Even so in
Christ shall all be made alive.
>> And Christ shall all be made alive. Yes.
Don't happen right away. Go ahead and
read.
>> But every man in his own order.
>> Every man in his own order. Go ahead.
>> Christ the first fruit.
>> Christ the first fruit. Then what?
>> After what they that are Christ at his
coming.
>> After the afterward they that are
Christ. When my brother
>> at his coming.
>> So who has got salvation?
>> No.
>> And he ain't going to give it to you
until he come.
>> Ain't nobody saved now then. Right.
That's right. according to what we can
read.
>> Skip down my brother to 35. What does it
say?
>> But some men will say, "How are the dead
raised up?"
>> Uhhuh.
>> And with what body do they come?
>> Respectfully, I don't think too many
people might ask this question nowadays
because everybody in heaven
>> they didn't up y
to be with the Lord. Somebody
said back then Paul said somebody will
say, "How the dead raised up and with
what body do they come?" What body
>> do they come? Read
>> thou food.
>> Uh-huh.
>> That which thou SEEST IS NOT QUICKENED
EXCEPT it die?
>> In other words, what you put in the
ground is not made alive, but it has to
die first. That's the process. Go ahead,
read.
>> And that which thou sest not that body
that shall be,
>> not that body that shall be. Go ahead,
read.
>> But bear grainhu, it make chants of
wheat or of some other grain.
>> In other words, it's not what goes in is
not what's going to come out. Brothers
and sisters, that's really all Paul is
saying. But go ahead and read.
>> But God giveth to the body as it had
pleased him
>> and to every seed his own body.
>> Wait a minute. Wait a minute. I thought
man had a shell and a soul inside of it.
>> At the funeral, brother so and so and
sister so and so. That's not them.
That's just a shell in the box. They
didn't made their homecoming. They
didn't went on back to heaven. But the
book say to every seed his own body. So
God didn't give you a shell. He gave you
a body which is a seed. Just like you
put a seed in the ground, it looks one
way. When it comes out, it's something
totally different. Right.
>> Yes, sir.
>> He's letting us know the order of things
right here. Skip down to verse 40,
brother.
>> There are also celestial bodies
>> and bodies terrestrial,
>> but the glory of the celestial is one
>> and the glory of the terrestrial is
another.
>> There's a difference between heavenly
and earthly bodies or spiritual bodies
and flesh and blood bodies. That's all
he's saying. Skip down to 42.
>> So also is the resurrection of the dead.
>> Uhhuh. It is sown in it is sown in
corruption. It is raised in
incorruption.
>> It is sown in corruption. It is raised
in incorruption. Perfect,
>> brothers and sisters. Isn't that
correct?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> It is sown in dishonor. It is raised in
glory.
>> Go ahead.
>> It is sown in weakness. It is raised in
power.
>> Didn't we read in Romans the first
chapter, Jesus became the son of God
with power by the resurrection of the
dead? That's right.
>> Go ahead and read, brother.
>> It is sown in a natural body. It is
raised a spiritual body. Read,
>> there is a natural body and there is a
spiritual body.
>> Go ahead, brother.
>> And so it is written,
>> uhhuh,
>> the first man, Adam, was made a living
soul.
>> Can we read that, brothers and sisters?
>> The breath of life was put in him.
That's when he became a living soul. Go
ahead and read.
>> The last Adam was made a quickening
spirit.
>> Wait a minute. The last Adam. Who is
that?
>> Jesus.
>> That's Jesus. He was made a quickening
spirit. Why is he also called the last
Adam? Because he's the first of his
kind. again the first one to die and
come out of the gravey spirit being with
life forever more. Do we understand what
we read brothers and sisters?
>> That's the perfecting part. I hope we
understand that. Now let's read second
Peter the first chapter. Now let's go to
second Peter.
Second Peter the first chapter.
We're talking about the perfecting of
the saints. get that glorified spiritual
body again like the father and Jesus.
That was their plan from day one.
>> Second Peter 1 and verse one. Brothers
and sisters, what does it say?
>> Simon Peter, a servant and an apostle of
Jesus Christ. To them that have obtained
like precious faith with us through the
righteousness of God and our savior
Jesus Christ. Grace and peace be
multiplied unto you through the
knowledge of God and of Jesus our Lord.
>> Uhhuh.
>> According as his divine power has given
unto us all things that pertain unto
life and godliness.
>> That's the eternal life and learning how
to become God. Go ahead and read.
>> Through the knowledge of him that hath
called us to glory and virtue.
>> That's the knowledge of his son Jesus
Christ. Go ahead and read.
>> Whereby are given unto us exceeding
great and precious promises. Oh, we
perceive exceeding great and precious
promises.
And the biggest promise of all is
eternal life. Go to 1 John 2:25 and read
that on your own. But go ahead and read.
>> That by these he might be partak
partakers of the divine nature.
>> Wait a minute. I'm confused again.
That we might be partakers of what kind
of nature, sir?
>> Divine nature.
>> That's godly nature. Right. Now, who are
partakers of flesh and blood?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Did we read Jesus likewise took part in
the same?
>> Yes, he did.
So by these you might be there's that
doubt that's up to you and me partakers
of the divine nature. Read my brother
>> having escaped the corruption that is in
the world through us.
>> So I hope we understand that this
perfection is about becoming just like
our lord and savior Jesus Christ when he
came out of the grave. That's what this
is all about brothers and sisters.
That's one part of it. Okay. Now let's
move on to the next leg. My brother read
the definition of the word minister for
the brothers and sisters. Go ahead.
>> Minister
>> fur to attend to the needs of someone to
serve.
>> Oh, so a minister is a servant.
>> Mhm.
>> You mean to tell me there's no big eyes
and little you just cuz somebody the
pastor of the church, he ain't supposed
to be all puffed up and looking down and
talking down to people. He's supposed to
have the mind of service. Wow. Read the
next definition. What it say?
>> Minister. Now a servant.
>> A servant. Now read the etmology of that
word, my brother. What it say? etmology
from the Latin minus.
>> From the Latin what?
>> Minus.
>> Minus
>> meaning less.
>> Meaning less. So even though I'm the
preacher today, I'm not supposed to turn
my nose up at y'all. No, sir.
>> And look down at y'all and preach fire
and brimstone and make y'all all scared
or whatever and then act like I'm not
subject to the same.
>> Paul talked about that, didn't he?
>> He did.
>> He said, "Man, I keep my body in
subjection because it'd be a shame after
all this preaching that I myself should
be what?" pass away.
>> But brother Marcus is scared as hell.
I'm just going to let y'all know that
>> every day I'm struggling. Don't look,
don't get it twisted. I'm struggling and
I'm fighting hard because this flesh is
a load in that direction.
>> Amen.
>> Make no mistake about it. But let's
proceed, brothers and sisters. Matthew
23.
This is serious business. This ain't no
joke. These folks playing church.
Matthew 23. Let's check out this
minister thing, y'all.
Matthew the 23rd chapter.
Let's pick it up at verse 1. Matthew 23
and one. What did it say?
>> This spake Jesus to the multitude and to
his disciples, saying,
>> Uhhuh.
>> THE SCRIBES AND THE PHARISEES SIT IN
MOSES'S SEAT.
>> Wait a minute. The office was already
established then, right?
>> Yes, sir.
>> They sitting in Moses' seat. Moses was
God's lawgiver and prophet to all
generations, right?
>> Yes, sir. So they said in his seat, what
they supposed to be doing? Teaching the
law. Right.
>> Go ahead.
>> Oh, therefore, whatsoever they bid, you
observe that observe and do, but do ye
not after their works. For they say and
do not.
>> Wait a minute. He just call them
hypocrites.
>> Yes.
>> He said what they teaching you, you do
that. Observe that. Because at least at
that time, they were teaching you right.
But he said, "Don't do after their
works, for they say and do not." They
are hypocrites. Skip down to verse five
to continue.
>> With all their works they do for to be
seen of men.
>> Uhhuh.
>> They make broad their felactories and
enlarge the borders of their garments.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And love the uppermost rooms and feasts
and the chief seats in the synagogue.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And greetings in the markets and to be
called of men rabbi, rabbi.
>> So they want to put on a show. They want
to look like a big shot. They want to be
in that, you know what they call in port
seat at these gatherings and things like
that. When they go out into the street,
they want people to call in rabbi. Y'all
know what that mean?
We only got one. Go ahead and read.
>> Skip.
>> Where we at? That was verse seven.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Skip down to verse 11. But we only
supposed to call Jesus right there. He's
our only master. Go ahead and read 11.
>> But he that is greatest among you shall
be your servant.
>> But he that is what?
>> Greatest among you shall be your
servant.
>> Do y'all see the mind of God right here?
>> Yes, sir.
>> He said the greatest among you is going
to be the one that's going to serve you.
that's going to do something for you.
Not boss you around and and act like
they all this and that.
>> That's right.
>> They're going to be a servant. Go ahead.
>> And whosoever shall exalt himself shall
be amazed.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And he that shall humble himself shall
be exalted.
>> So in other words, the one that puffs
himself up, I'm going to bring down.
>> Yes.
>> But the one that humbles himself, that's
the one I'm going to lift up. Y'all see
that?
>> Amen.
>> That's what the Lord is saying right
here. That was the end of that, brother.
Yes, sir.
>> Let's go to Matthew 20. Back up to
Matthew 20, brother and sister. Matthew
20. Look at some more things about this.
So he said, "The greatest among you is
going to be your servant."
Matthew 20 and verse 20. Matthew 20 and
verse 20. Let's take a look at this
little story.
A woman came and made a request of the
Lord concerning her sons. Verse 20. What
does it say? Then came to him the mother
of Zebedes children with her sons
worshiping him and desiring a certain
thing of him.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And he said unto her, "What w?"
>> He said, "Okay, what do you want?" Go
ahead and read.
>> She said unto him, "Grant that these my
two sons may sit, the one on thy right
hand and the other on the left in thy
kingdom."
>> Says, "And your kingdom." Go ahead,
read.
>> But Jesus answered and said, "Ye know
not what you ask." Uh-huh.
>> Are you able to drink of the cup that I
shall drink of, and to be baptized with
the baptism that I am baptized with?
>> Uh-huh.
>> They say unto him, we are able.
>> And what did he say?
>> And he saith unto them, Ye shall drink
indeed of my cup, and be baptized with
the baptism that I am baptized with.
>> For what?
>> But to sit on my right hand and on my
left is not mine to give, but it shall
be given to them for whom it is prepared
of my father.
>> So, do y'all see the request that she
made? In other words, you want something
to be kind of special, right?
>> Let's pursue it. Read.
>> And when the 10 heard it, they were
moved with indignation against the two
brethren.
>> So when the other apostles heard this,
they got mad. They was upset. Right.
>> That's right.
>> So Jesus is looking at this and he's
going to weigh in. Verse 25. What does
it say?
>> But Jesus called them unto him and said,
"Ye know that the presence of the
Gentiles exercise dominion over them,
>> and they that are great exercise
authority upon them." He said this is
how the Gentiles behave. He said they
that are in charge, you know, they
rulers and stuff or they supervisors or
whatever. It says they exercise dominion
over the people. In other words, hey,
I'm the boss. Shut up and do what I say
>> right now. I don't care. They kind of
mean, you know, exercising that
authority over. That's what the Lord is
saying, right?
>> That's right.
>> But he said, look, I don't want y'all to
be this way. Go ahead and read.
>> BUT IT SHALL NOT BE SO AMONG YOU.
>> But what? But whosoever WILL BE GREAT
AMONG YOU, let him be your minister.
>> You all see the consistency here? He's
equating greatness with humility and
service. That's the mindset that we all
should have as servants of God. What can
I do to help somebody else?
>> That's right.
>> You know, I'm I had this revelation some
years ago. I was sitting at the feast in
Riverdale and I was looking at the
brothers working hard, stacking those
chairs up and stuff. I'm like, man, I
can't do that because I had a whole back
injury, right? I said, but man, the Lord
put that spirit on me. said, "I need to
do something. Let me ask the brothers
next time, can I help serve in the line
or do something?" And I started helping,
you know, serve the food sometimes and
things like that. But at that point, I
didn't know I was going to ultimately
become a teacher. Brothers and sisters,
I'm not saying that. But what I'm saying
is that spirit came on me. Look, I've
been served. Now, it's time for me to
serve. It's time for me to do something.
I'm reading stuff like this and the book
just said, "Let the greatest among you,
let him be your minister." Isn't that
correct?
>> That's just the mindset we should have.
What can we do to help someone else?
Right? It's not all about us. But go
ahead and read, brother. What does it
say?
>> Verse 27.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And whosoever will be chief among you,
let him be your servant.
>> He said it again. He's going to give the
ultimate example about himself. Read.
>> Even as the son of man came not to be
ministered unto.
>> Wait a minute. He didn't come to be
served. That's what the Lord is saying
here, right?
>> That's right.
>> He didn't come to lay down in the C,
have some people fanning him with big
fans, and feed them fruit. Yes, sir. He
said, "The Son of Man came not to be
ministered unto and not to be served,
but what, brother?"
>> But to minister,
>> to serve. Y'all see that?
>> How did you do that? Go ahead, read it.
>> AND TO GIVE HIS LIFE A RANSOM FOR ME.
>> He made the ultimate sacrifice. He gave
his life as a ransom for men. That's all
man.
>> Amen.
>> Anybody that would take advantage of it,
didn't it say his grace for him we
stand?
>> Yes.
>> Then we read that, brother. Do you all
understand that the mind of a minister
is supposed to be humble and he's
supposed to be thinking about what can I
do to serve the flock of God? Do you all
understand?
>> Not fleece them, not take advantage of
like I said to get a boat or airplane or
something or Rolls Russ. Mark chapter 3.
Mark chapter 3.
Let's find out some more things,
brothers and sisters. Mark chapter 3.
Y'all all right, brothers and sisters?
>> Amen.
>> Praise God.
>> Mark 3:13. What does it say, my brother?
>> And he goeth up into a mountain, and
callth unto him whom he would.
>> This is Jesus. He called unto him whom
he would. Go ahead and read.
>> And they came unto him.
>> What did he do?
>> And he ordained 12.
>> He ordained 12. He set 12 apart. Go
ahead and read.
>> That they should be with him.
>> And do what else?
>> And that he might send them forth to
preach.
>> Oh, he just didn't pick 12 apostles to
hang out with them.
>> Or sit around and break bread, drink
wine.
>> Yes, sir.
>> He set them apart. Then he sent them
forth to preach. And we going to find
out what because there's a particular
message. There's one spirit. Didn't we
read that?
>> One spirit. Yes, sir.
>> Let's turn over to Matthew 10 now. Back
to Matthew this time, chapter 10. Let's
see something.
Matthew chapter 10.
He ordained 12 and he sent them forth to
preach.
Matthew chapter 10. Everybody got it?
>> We're going to read verse one and then
we're going to skip. Matthew chapter 10
verse one. What it say, brother? And
when he had called unto him his 12
disciples, he gave them power against
unclean spirit to cast them out and to
heal all manner of sickness and all
manner of disease.
>> The Lord always prepares his servants.
He did this because he knows that
there's a lot of disbelief or unbelief
in the world. And sometimes man need a
little sign or something, right? So he
gave his apostles power to deal with all
that stuff. But skip down to verse 5.
What did it say? These 12 Jesus sent
forth and commanded them, saying,
>> what did he say?
>> GO NOT INTO THE WAY OF THE Gentiles and
into any city of the Samaritans. Enter
ye not.
>> Whoa, wait a minute. The Lord said,
don't go in the way of the Gentiles.
>> And don't go into any city of the
Samaritans. Why? Because at this time,
he was on a mission to get his priest
back in order, back on a dime, as
brother would say.
>> Right. If you're the priest, you don't
have any understanding. Who you going to
teach?
>> So, he wanted Israel to get back
straight first. Brothers and sisters, we
see that.
>> Yes.
>> He said, "Don't go to the Gentile. Don't
go into Samaria." Because in Samaria,
the Israelites that once lived there had
been taken away captive and replaced
with strangers. So, he said, "I don't
even want you to go there." Remember
when he went into Samaria, the woman at
the well engaged?
>> He wasn't even going to talk to her at
first. She even said the Jews have no
deal with the Samaritan. But this is
why. Go ahead. Three, but go rather to
the lost sheep of the house of Israel.
>> Go rather to the lost sheep of the house
of Israel. But there's something he
wanted them to do, my brother.
>> Yes, sir.
>> What did he say?
>> And as you go, UH-HUH. PREACH.
>> DO WHAT?
>> PREACH.
>> PREACH. What did he say?
>> Sayingh, the kingdom of heaven is at
hand.
>> Oh, so he told them, he separated them
to preach. And now he's giving them a
message. He said, go and preach saying
the kingdom of heaven is at hand. Right.
That's right. And we know what
understanding that's the kingdom that's
going to come from heaven, right?
>> But it's at hand. H to be at hand. This
was over 2,000 years ago, right?
>> I got a question, brothers and sisters.
I ain't nobody tell is the kingdom of
heaven.
>> Still not here, right?
>> So what did he mean the kingdom of
heaven is at hand? Because death is on
the table. We only have so much time. So
with the time that we have while we have
the breath of life, we're supposed to be
preparing ourselves to be qualified to
enter the kingdom when it comes. Like we
can read in Hebrews 11, the elders of
saying that could report by way of their
faith. That's what we're supposed to be
doing. Getting a good resume that's
going to speak for us whether or sleep,
brothers and sisters. Do we understand
that?
>> Yes.
>> So the message is still the same even
today because God gave man so much time,
seven days. And once that time is up,
here come the father, brothers and
sisters. But he said, "Go and preach
saying the kingdom of heaven is at
hand." Back up to Matthew 4.
Matthew the 4th chapter.
Let's see what else he's saying. Matthew
4.
Because there's something you have to
do. There's something you have to
acknowledge if you're going to serve
God, if you're going to ultimately get
into his kingdom. Let's find out what
that is.
>> Matthew 4, let's read verse 17, brother.
What does it say?
>> From that time, Jesus began to preach
and to say.
>> What did he say?
>> Repent.
>> Do what?
>> Oh, repent. Go ahead.
>> For the kingdom of heaven is at hand.
>> So, if you want to get into the kingdom
of heaven that's going to come from
heaven and be on the earth, you and I
have to do what, brothers and sisters?
>> Repent. Repent. That's not just saying,
"I'm sorry, Lord. I'm sorry." That ain't
going to cut it. Repentance is a change
of behavior that comes from a change of
what?
>> Your mind. Didn't we read a new heart
was I going to give them? That's right.
>> And I'm going to put my spirit in them.
>> So, you have to turn from sinful
behavior
and obey God's voice and keep his
commandments. That's true repentance.
And of course, we know you got to get
baptized in the name of Jesus and all
that, but it says, "Repent for the
kingdom of heaven is at hand." Skip
down, my brother, to verse 23. What does
that say?
>> And Jesus went about all Galilee,
teaching in their synagogues.
>> Oh, Jesus was a minister of God.
>> For the truth of God, a minister of
circumcision for the truth of God.
>> That's right.
>> We can read that in Luke the 4th
chapter, right?
>> He always went into the church and
taught. Y'all go ahead and read.
>> And preaching the gospel of the kingdom.
Preaching what?
>> The gospel of the kingdom.
>> So, not only do you have to repent
this gospel is the gospel of the
kingdom.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Right. Not prosperity,
not blessing, and all this kind of
stuff. He's preaching and teaching the
gospel of the kingdom. Go ahead and
read.
>> And healing all manner of sickness and
all manner of disease among the people.
>> Are we following, brothers and sisters?
This is what you're supposed to be doing
when you're standing in this office.
Preparing the people to walk through the
gates of the city when they come.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Matthew 24.
Matthew 24. Brothers and sisters.
>> This is simple, but the world just don't
seem to know this. Like I said, they
come up to places like this, pull, and
tell you all kind of stories that you
cannot read in the book.
>> Sorry.
>> What brother call the fairy tale.
They own.
>> Let's find something else out. Matthew
24. We kind of touched on it already,
but let's read it again. Matthew 24 and
14. Go ahead and read, brother.
>> And this gospel of the kingdom SHALL BE
PREACHED IN ALL THE world for a WITNESS
UNTO ALL NATIONS.
>> THEN WHAT?
>> And then shall the end come.
>> So this gospel of the kingdom shall be
preached in all the world for a witness
unto all nations. is going to witness
for you or against you. But it said,
"Then shall the end come." That's
talking about the world as we know it.
This earth is going to still be here.
But he created it to be inhabited
forever. Praise. Isn't that correct?
>> That's right.
>> Now, skip up to verse 13. What it say?
>> But he that shall endure until the end.
>> But he that shall endure until when?
>> The end.
>> Again, the end of your natural life
until the Lord come back. Go ahead and
read.
>> The same shall be saved.
>> No, brother. The same is saved.
>> The same shall be saved. name shall be
saved. Future tense. That's why we got
to hold on to that which we've been
given. Brothers and sist
right over to chapter 25.
Take a look at it because brothers and
sisters, people are trying to circumvent
Jesus and get right to the father.
Again, that's a me a message or doctrine
from Satan. He wants to go up yonder. He
got everybody thinking that got their
head in the cloud. But the son's kingdom
is coming to the earth first.
That's what a lot of people don't
understand. They trying to get to heaven
where heaven is coming down. That's
right.
>> First the son, then the father. That's
the two order of things. Let's read
about it. 25-31. What does it say, my
brother?
>> When the son of man shall come in his
glory.
>> The son of man. We know that's talking
Jesus. But he's going to come in his
glory. His glorified spiritual body at
the end of days. What it say?
>> And all the holy angels with him.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Then shall he sit upon the throne of his
glory.
>> He's going to sit upon the throne of his
glory. And that's the throne of David.
Brothers and sisters, go ahead and read.
>> And before him shall be gathered all
nations.
>> How many?
>> All nations.
>> During the millennium period, the
thousand year reign, before him shall be
gathered all nations. Go ahead and read.
>> And he shall separate them one from
another. AS THE SHEPHERD DIVIDED HIS
SHEEP FROM THE GOATS.
>> Wait a minute. He going to separate
them.
>> Yes, sir.
>> It says, as a shepherd divided his sheep
from the goats.
>> Wow. He's going to make a distinction
between the people.
>> But I thought everybody was saved. I
thought everybody's okay.
>> No, he's going to scrutinize some
things, brothers and sisters.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> And he shall set the sheep on his right
hand, but the goats on the left.
>> And we are talking people, right?
>> That's right.
>> You got sheep and you got goats. That's
what we're learning right here. Go ahead
and read.
>> Then shall the king say unto THEM ON HIS
RIGHT HAND.
>> Come ye BLESSED OF MY FATHER, INHERIT
THE KINGDOM PREPARED for you from the
foundation of the world. Now, we just
went from the coming of the Lord all the
way to the white throne judgment.
Brothers and sisters, because the
kingdom prepared from the foundation of
the world is the father's kingdom. Yes,
sir.
>> Like brother always say, it was ready
for us, but we were not ready for it
because Adam fell away from day one.
That's right.
>> He said, "Come ye blessed my father and
have the kingdom prepared for you from
the foundation of the world because now
it's time for new Jerusalem to come
down." But let's see who's going to get
into this kingdom. Skip down to 41. What
it say? Then shall he also,
>> excuse me, then shall he say also unto
them on the left hand,
>> depart from me, ye cursed, into
everlasting FIRE,
>> PREPARE FOR THE DEVIL and his angels.
>> Whoa. So the sheep on the right hand go
into life.
>> But the ones on the left, the ghosts on
the left, he going to say, "Depart from
me, you curse in the everlasting fire.
You going to mess around and get
yourself into a punishment that was made
for Satan and his angels. All the ones
that Michael and his host kicked out of
heaven. Do we see this, brothers and
sisters? Yes, sir.
>> This wasn't even made for man. But since
the Lord going to make you live forever
and change you, he said, "Everybody
rebelled against me going there."
>> Yes, sir.
>> That's what he said, right?
>> That's right.
>> Skip down to 46. What it say, brother?
>> And these SHALL GO AWAY INTO EVERLASTING
PUNISHMENT.
>> BUT WHAT ABOUT THE RIGHTEOUS, my
brother?
>> But the righteous into life, eternal.
>> Do we see two locks here, brothers and
sisters?
>> We got eternal life and eternal
damnation. Yes, sir.
>> This is the message. Get your house in
order. Understand what this gospel is
about. It's about the coming of the
kingdom of God. And you must get
salvation in order to be a partaker.
First starting with the kingdom of the
son that you may be so blessed to reign
with him for that thousand years, but at
the very least that you're qualified at
the white foot of judgment by your
works. Yes. To get into the father's
kingdom, new Jerusalem when it come
down. Are we following brothers and
sisters?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Now, let's read the word, the definition
of the word edify. This is the last leg.
We're in the home stretch, y'all. Y'all
good?
>> All right. Read the word. The definition
of that word edify, my brother. What
does it say?
>> Edify. Verb. To instruct or improve
someone morally or intellectually, to
educate, to teach.
>> So when he said the edifying of the body
of Christ, he's talking about teaching
the people. Right.
>> Read that next definition. Uh the word,
the etmology of that word. What does it
say?
>> Etmology.
>> To build up, strengthen. Oh, I'm
supposed to be building you all up in
this house through the word of God. I'm
supposed to be strengthening you.
>> Yes, sir.
>> So that you can walk this walk of faith
and get the salvation that the go that
God the Father Christ are offering us.
>> That's right.
>> Okay, that makes sense to me. Read the
definition of the word edifying. What it
say?
>> Edifying. Uhhuh.
>> Adjective.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Providing moral or intellectual
instruction.
>> Educating, teaching.
>> Educating and teaching. Read the rest of
that.
>> Compare with edifice. A building or
dwelling. Oh, so those words have the
same root. Edifice and edifying and
edification.
>> Yes, sir.
>> It's about building, right? Dwelling.
Again, we are all a part of the
household of God through the word of
God, through preaching and teaching, I'm
supposed to be firmly cementing you in
this house so that you won't be moved,
brothers and sisters. Like the book say
with every wind of doctrine. People come
up with all kind of stuff. But when you
understand the precepts in this book,
somebody come to you with some nonsense,
you be like, "Man, get away from me with
that such stuff." What thus sayeth the
Lord, thus and thus and so forth. Am I
right, brothers and sisters?
>> That's right.
>> First Peter the second chapter. 1 Peter
chapter 2. Let's deal with this
edification.
1 Peter 2. Because we read he gave all
these individuals for the perfecting of
the saints, for the work of the
ministry, and for the edifying of the
body of Christ. Right?
>> Yes, sir.
>> That's what we read.
Peter,
first Peter
chapter 2,
we're going to start at verse one,
brothers and sisters.
1 Peter 2 and one. Let's take a look and
see what this has to offer. Go ahead.
>> Wherefore laying aside all malice and
all guile and hypocrisies and envies and
all evil speaking,
>> do what?
>> As newborn babes, desire the sincere
milk of the word that he may grow
thereby.
>> Oh, so you have to be humble
and acknowledge that you don't know
anything. We have to be teachable,
brothers and sisters.
>> Some people you can't tell anything.
I've been dealing with a brother online
that just won't listen. He wants to run
and talk and say things. Some of the
stuff he says is right, but then he goes
off on tangents. And I try to correct
the brother. He won't receive it. I
said, "Bro, I sat in front of brother
boy for years and didn't open my mouth.
There's nothing wrong with learning in
silence. Once you have something to say,
then the Lord will put you in that
position to say something." As new for
babes desire the sincere milk of the
word because that's how you and I grow.
Go ahead and read.
>> If so be ye have tasted that the Lord is
gracious.
>> He's very gracious. But I want us to pay
attention here. Read verse four.
>> To whom coming? As unto a living stone
>> as unto what, brother?
>> A living stone.
>> What we talking about?
>> Jesus.
>> He's a living stone. Right.
>> So it be
>> disallowed indeed of men.
>> Uhhuh.
>> But chosen of God and precious.
>> He's the Messiah, the Christ, the
anointed one. Right.
>> Yes.
>> He's the one that the Lord chose to do
this great works for mankind. Right. But
now there's a transition when it comes
to us because remember we're all a part
of the same house, right?
>> There's a transition. He's a living
stone. But what about us? Read that next
verse.
>> He also as lively stones.
>> As what, my brother?
>> Lively.
>> Oh, wait a minute. H Jesus is a living
stone. Again, he came, he died, he rose,
and he was a spirit being again in this
case, right?
>> So, he's a living stone. He's not dying
anymore. But we are alive stones. What
does that mean, brothers and sisters?
That we have the potential to become
living stones. Do y'all see that?
>> Yes, sir.
>> He's the chief cornerstone, the head of
the body. We're in the house. We're his
brothers as long as we walk in his ways.
That's right.
>> And we have the potential to become what
he is. But at the time of appointed, I
want us to see that. Y'all see that,
brothers and sisters?
>> Man, he is a living stone. We are lively
stone. Start at five again. Ye also as
lively souls are built up a SPIRITUAL
HOUSE. WHAT MY BROTHER?
>> A SPIRITUAL HOUSE.
>> Built up a spiritual house through that
word that we just read about. Go ahead.
Read.
>> And holy priesthood.
>> Uhhuh.
>> TO OFFER UP SPIRITUAL sacrifices
acceptable to God by Jesus Christ.
>> Oh, because y'all know when he came and
died, he ended or terminated the old
covenant, right?
>> He did.
>> Under which animal sacrifice was added,
right?
>> Yes, sir.
>> So, they were making carnal sacrifices
for sin. Right.
>> That's right. But here says he came and
died and and we're in the house. He's
saying offer up spiritual sacrifices
acceptable to God by him. So what are
spiritual sacrifices?
When you're doing things in
righteousness, brothers and sisters,
keeping the Sabbath, keeping the 10,
keeping the dietary law, keeping the
Passover and the feast days, those are
spiritual sacrifices. Do we understand
what we read, brothers and sisters?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Now, let's go to Ecclesiastes the 12th
chapter.
Ecclesiastes chapter 12.
Again, we have to be humble enough
to be taught to allow ourselves be
taught. We have to acknowledge that we
don't know anything.
>> That's right.
>> You can't pour anything into a full
vessel.
>> That's right. Ain't no room.
Ecclesiastes 12.
>> Let's start reading at verse number
nine. Ecclesiastes 12 and 9. What does
it say?
>> And moreover, because the preacher was
wise.
>> Because the preacher was what, my
brother?
>> Wise.
>> What did he do?
>> He still taught the people knowledge.
>> Oh, the wise preacher is going to impart
some knowledge unto you, brothers and
sisters.
>> That's his job. Go ahead, read.
>> Yeah. He gave good heed and sought out
and said in order many proverbs.
>> So the first thing he did was paying
attention to himself.
>> Yes sir.
>> I can't give you anything. And I'm not
saying I'm wise in that sense. I'm very
humble brothers and sisters. But you
going to make that judgment for
yourself. But he said he still talked to
people knowledge and he gave good heed.
He paid attention and did some study and
some reading and sought out and set in
order a lot of things that you can read
in this Bible. Like for example the
spirit of God. Every time you see that,
it doesn't mean the same thing. That's
right. So, our pastor came up with a
lesson with four legs to show you just
some of the ways this word can be used
because if you use it in the wrong
context, what's going to happen? You're
going to get the wrong understanding.
Right?
>> So, we have to set these things in
order. Again, it's like put pieces to a
puzzle together, right?
>> It says, "He gave good heed and saw and
set in order many proverbs." Go ahead
and read, brother.
>> The preacher sought to find out
acceptable words.
>> What kind of word?
>> Acceptable. Not his own
>> acceptable.
>> Not what he told or felt.
>> Acceptable words.
>> Not what he believed.
>> Acceptable word.
>> Acceptable words. He sought to find an
acceptable word. Brothers and sisters,
let's see where he got those acceptable
words from. Read.
>> And that which was written was upright.
>> And that which was what, my brother?
>> Written.
>> Oh, the acceptable words were already
written.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Okay. Go ahead and read.
>> Even words of truth.
>> Because those words are true. Go ahead
and read
>> verse 11. The words of the wise are as
gold
>> and as nails fashioned by the masters of
assemblu
>> which are given from one shepherd.
>> Y'all understand what a goat is, brother
and sister?
>> Right.
>> It's like a shepherd's stick. When the
sheep start getting out, you know, going
in the wrong direction, he start poking
and prying them.
>> Uhuh. Don't go over there. Come over
here. Uh-uh. Don't go over there. Come
over here. Stay right here on this
straight narrow. Spiritually, y'all
understand?
>> That leads to life, right?
>> That's right.
>> So, this word going to keep you on the
right path. the straight narrow path
that leads to life.
>> And it says as nails fastened by the
masters of assemblies. Because once you
study this word, you get some
understanding. You're no longer a
novice. You're supposed to know what
you're talking about. If you don't know
it, don't say it. Right.
>> Yes, sir.
>> And it says that I give him from how
many shepherds?
>> One shepherd.
>> Who was that y'all?
>> Jesus.
>> All right, keep reading.
>> And further, by these my son, be it
monuh
>> of making many books there is no end.
>> Uhhuh. and much study is a weariness of
the flesh.
>> So we don't need the apocrypha.
>> We don't need the Egyptian book of the
dead.
>> We don't need the book of Joshua.
>> We don't need the book of Enoch. That's
what this is talking about. This says of
making many books there's no end. Every
other day these Hebrews come up with
something else. But it says and much
study is awareness of the flesh. Talking
about all those outside things that
don't have anything to do with the word
of God. Brothers and sisters, that's why
we deal with this book from Genesis to
Revelation.
>> Amen.
>> We have everything in these pages that
we need
>> to help us work out our salvation,
brothers and sisters. Isn't that right?
>> That's right.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> Letter to the conclusion of the whole
matter.
>> Fear God and keep his commandments,
>> for this is the whole duty of man.
>> This is the whole duty of Israel,
brother.
>> The whole duty of man.
>> Oh, this is a man thing. Huh?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead and read what. For God shall
bring every work into judgment with
every secret thing, whether it be good
or whether it be evil.
>> We just read the Lord was going to bring
the people in front of them
>> and separate them. Didn't we read that?
>> That's right.
>> He's going to look at our works,
brothers and sisters. We have to have a
care, right?
>> Second Timothy chapter 3. We got two
more spots after this. Second Timothy
chapter 3.
I hope this making sense, brothers and
sisters.
>> Praise God.
Second Timothy chapter 3,
we're talking about being edified in the
body of Christ that through his word
cuz it's our knowledge, brothers and
sisters, that's going to help us obtain
that salvation every time according
Timothy 3,
let's start at verse 14, brother. Go
ahead with me.
>> But continue thou in the things which
thou hast learned and hast been assured
of.
>> Uhhuh. knowing of whom thou has learned
them.
>> This an admonition Paul has given
Timothy. Go ahead and read.
>> And that from a CHILD THOU HAS KNOWN THE
HOLY SCRIPTURES.
>> From a child you have known what?
>> The holy scripture.
>> The holy scripture from Genesis to
Malachi. Because that's what they had
then. Right.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> Which are able to make thee wise unto
salvation.
>> They are automatically able to make thee
wise unto salvation.
>> are able to make you wise.
>> Able. You have to accept them and deal
with. They're able to make you wise unto
salvation. Go ahead.
>> Through faith which is in Christ Jesus.
>> And if you got to believe in it, if it
all starts and ends with the Lord Jesus
Christ, brothers and sisters, what it
say?
>> All scripture is given by inspiration of
God.
>> HOW MUCH?
>> ALL.
>> All of it come from God. The book say
the Lord gave the word, but great was
the company of those that published it.
It all come from God. Go ahead and read.
>> And is profitable for doctrine,
>> for reproofh, for correction, for
instruction and righteousness.
>> Oh, this is that good doctrine we read
about. Forsake you not my law.
>> Yes, sir. It says for reproof and
correction. When someone is telling you
something that don't line up with the
book, by all means you can correct them,
but you be patient and you pull up the
scripture.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Right. She says for instruction and
righteousness. This is how we are
edified. We have to be instructed
through the word of God. In order to
become righteous, because righteousness
is of the law, a
>> Yes, sir. Yes.
>> Read.
>> That the man of God may be perfect.
>> That the man of God may be what?
Perfect. Y'all see the connection,
brother and sister? That the man of God
may be perfect. GO AHEAD. TRULY
FURNISHED UNTO all good works.
>> Furnished unto what?
>> All good works.
>> Good works.
>> Good work.
>> Oh, so that's bad works then, huh?
>> They are. Yes.
>> Okay. I'm just asking a question. Acts
chapter 8. One more after this, brothers
and sisters. Acts chapter 8.
Let's take a look at something that
happened here.
There's an individual that was returning
from Jerusalem. He's going back to
Ethiopia. He's an Israelite going back
to where he stayed.
Let's see what this has to offer. Acts 8
26. What does it say?
>> And the angel of the Lord spake unto
Philillip, saying, arise and go toward
the south unto the way that goeth down
from Jerusalem unto Gaza, which is
desert.
>> And the angel of the Lord told Philillip
to do this. Go ahead and read. And he
arose and wentu and behold a man of
Ethiopia and unic of great authority
under Kandaki queen of the Ethiopia who
had the charge of all her treasure and
had come to Jerusalem for to worship
>> was returning and sitting in his
chariotas the prophet.
>> So he stopped along the way back to
Ethiopia brothers and sisters he was
sitting in his chariot and he was
reading Isaiah the prophet. He's reading
the book right?
>> Yes sir.
>> What verse 29 say? Go ahead. Then the
spirit said unto Philip, "Go near and
join thyel to this chariot."
>> Oh, wait a minute. Brother Marx is
confused again. In verse 26, it said,
"And the angel of the Lord spake unto
Philillip." Right.
>> Mhm.
>> Right here in verse 29, it said, "Then
the spirit said unto Philillip," right?
What happened?
>> One sing.
>> Oh, angels are spirit.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Okay. Thank you for that clarification.
>> 29. My brother, read. Then the spirit
said unto Philillip, "Go near and join
thyself to this chariot." And Philip ran
good to him and heard him read the
prophet Isaiah and said, "Understandest
thou what thou readest?"
>> Oh, listen is the principal thing. But
without thy getting what?
>> Understand?
>> Understanding. He said as he's listening
to him read the book of Isaiah the
prophet, do you understand what you're
reading? Because some people actually do
read the book, but they never come to a
place of understanding. brothers and
sisters because they think that they can
get it all on their own. But we read the
Lord gave these men for these reasons,
right?
>> To help us get some understanding,
>> But what did this brother say? And I'm
going to say this, a lot of people need
to take heed and look at the humility of
this brother. Yes.
>> It will serve them well. Read the next
verse.
>> Verse 31.
>> And he said, "How can I except SOME MAN
SHOULD GUIDE ME?"
>> HOW can I except the Holy Ghost come
down and overshadow me?
>> Except some man should guide me. Oh, he
understood that God says men to teach
men, right?
>> Yes, sir.
>> He said, "How can I understand except
some man should guide me, teach me,
right? Edify me." Read, brother.
>> And he desired Philillip that he would
come up and sit with him.
>> He said, "Man, look, I don't know what's
going on. Come on up there and show me."
Right?
>> Yes.
>> What verse was that, brother?
>> That was verse 31.
>> Keep reading.
>> The place of the scripture which he ran
was this. He was led as a sheep to the
slaughter and like a lamb dump before
his sheer.
>> Uh-huh. So open he not his mouth.
>> Uhhuh.
>> In his humiliation his judgment was
taken away.
>> And who shall declare his generation?
For his life is taken from the earth.
>> So he was reading Isaiah the 53rd
chapter. Right.
>> Mhm.
>> Now we know that's talking to Jesus all
day long. Right.
>> That's right.
>> But this brother didn't know. Let's see
what he said. Go ahead and read.
>> And the unic answered Philillip and
said, "I pray thee of whom speaketh the
prophet of this?" Uhhuh.
>> Of himself or of some other man? He
said, "Look, I'm reading the Bible, but
I don't know if Isaiah is talking about
himself or somebody else. Help me out."
Yes, sir.
>> Y'all see the humility that this brother
has?
>> Read it to me.
>> Said, "I don't know. I need you to
instruct me. Help me out. Tell me what's
going on here. Go ahead and read what
Philip do."
>> Then Philip opened his mouth and begin
at the same scripture.
>> What he do?
>> And preached unto him, Jesus.
>> He gave this brother some understanding.
He said, "Look, this is talking to
Jesus. Let me show you how." Y'all
understand?
But the brother was humble enough to
receive instruction. That's the point I
wanted to make here. Now, let's go to
the last place. Let's go to the book of
Nehemiah, 8th chapter.
Nehemiah chapter 8.
This is our last scripture, brothers and
sisters.
Nehemiah 8.
Nehemiah chapter 8, we're going to start
reading at verse one.
This is the time of Ezra and Nehemiah
after they had been allowed to go back
to rebuild the city and the wall and all
that stuff. Nehemiah 8 and 1. What does
it say?
>> And all the people gathered themselves
together as one man into the street that
was before the water gate. And they
spake unto Ezra the scribe to bring the
book of the law of Moses, which the Lord
had commanded to Israel.
>> They got the book of the law. Go ahead
and read.
>> And Ezra the priest brought the law
before the congregation, both men and
women.
>> And all that could hear with
understanding.
>> That could hear with what?
>> Understanding.
>> So everybody that could comprehend the
words was standing before these
brothers. Right. Yes,
>> sir.
>> Go ahead.
>> Upon the first day of the seventh month,
>> Uh-huh.
>> And he read therein before the street
that was before the Watergate from the
morning until midday. Uh-huh.
>> But for the men and the women, AND THOSE
THAT DIDN'T UNDERSTAND. Go ahead.
>> And the ears of all the people were
attentive unto the book of the law.
>> Do y'all see what was going on from the
morning until midday? They spent some
time dealing with the scripture,
brothers and sisters.
>> Wow. Nowadays, people don't want to sit
down and listen to nothing.
>> You know, they don't want to come and
have a holy congregation.
>> Absolutely.
>> But it said they did this from morning
until midday. And those that could
understand the ear is of all the people
were attentive and were really paying
attention unto the book of the law. Skip
down to verse five to continue my drop.
>> And Ezra opened the book in the sight of
all the people.
>> Uhhuh.
>> So he was above all the people.
>> And when he opened it, all the people
stood up.
>> So he kind of was like in a little pull
pit type situation, right?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Now skip down to verse eight. What it
say?
>> So they read in the book in the law of
God distinctly.
>> They read in the book in the law of God
distinctly. They did not come up with
their own private interpretation.
>> No sir.
>> They read on the line, right?
>> That's right.
>> And what else?
>> And gave the sense.
>> And gave what, brother?
>> They gave the sense.
>> The people got some sense.
>> Oh, I understand what the Lord is
saying. Keep my commandments so I can
live now and forever.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Right. So, read.
>> And call them to understand the read.
>> And cause them TO DO WHAT?
>> UNDERSTAND the read.
>> Again, brothers and sisters, with all
thy getting
understanding. Do we see that brothers
and sisters? Yes sir.
>> So again just a quick recap. This is the
ministry of Jesus Christ. The father
sent him to do this work to start the
process of reconciling, recovering and
redeeming us back to him. And he has
employed men throughout all generations
to continue in that process. I don't
have the autonomy, the liberty, or the
freedom to come up here and stand before
you and tell you what's on my mind. That
would be a waste of my time and yours.
Okay? Again, people don't understand
that we fell from grace from day one
when Adam sinned against God. But the
Lord Jesus when he died, he restored our
prospects of gaining immortality in the
good side of God's kingdom. Yet again,
that's why I say I restored that which I
took not away. Right? Because brothers
and sisters, again, I don't care what
you're dealing with out of the
scripture, these subjects and titles
that we teach are all supposed to go in
our spiritual tool bag in our arsenal,
right? so that we can continue to fight
this fight of faith because we are in a
spiritual battle every day. Right? So we
can continue to walk this walk of faith
and endure until the end. Again, the
purpose of the ministry, service unto
salvation. That's the end all be all.
And we read it. He gave these brothers
to perfect the saints to work in his
ministry, his vineyard, and to edify the
body of Christ. Isn't that correct,
brothers and sisters?
>> Amen.
>> So, I hope someone got some edification
out of the lesson. Thank you all for
your time.
>> AMEN.
HEAT. HEAT.